🎵
🎵
The Fall Education takes two
秋期教育には 2 回かかります
As the19 month is over
19ヶ月が終わるので
impress many welcome each other
多くの人を感動させる お互いを歓迎する
Kings
キングス
Playing
遊ぶ
down
下
civil
民
movie
映画
then
それから
It means that you all have a speech in your hands.
それは皆さんがスピーチを手にしていることを意味します。
Of course you can take a look first
もちろん最初に見てみるのもいいですよ
and after listening to the speech
そしてスピーチを聞いた後
you go back and read it again
戻ってもう一度読んでください
Then there will be a deeper experience
そうすればさらに深い経験ができるでしょう
You only need to understand when you go back
戻ったときにのみ理解する必要があります
understandable words
わかりやすい言葉
That's very rewarding
それはとてもやりがいがあります
content of that speech
そのスピーチの内容
I will be introduced by teacher Wang Yuling
王玉玲先生から紹介してもらいます
at the beginning
初めに
I still put his simple travel law
私はまだ彼の単純な旅行法を適用しています
with his glorious deeds
彼の輝かしい行為によって
Give you a brief introduction
簡単に紹介します
Dr. Wang Yuling came to the Department of Physics in 1979 and graduated
王玉玲博士は1979年に物理学科に来て卒業しました。
Then after graduation
それから卒業後は
to the University of Chicago in 1988
1988年にシカゴ大学へ
PhD in Physics
物理学博士号
Then go to the famous Vel Lab in the United States
続いてアメリカの有名なヴェルラボへ。
to do postdoctoral research
ポスドク研究をする
Come back and join us in 1991
1991 年に戻ってきて参加しましょう
Original branch Re-researcher To researcher To current specific researcher
元支部 再研究者 研究者へ 現特定研究者へ
He has performed very well all the way
彼はずっと素晴らしいパフォーマンスを見せてくれた
In terms of research he has two main themes
研究に関して、彼には 2 つの主要なテーマがあります。
The first topic is the surface of the rice
最初のトピックはこの耐性米の表面です
The mechanism underlying the formation of this surface structure
この表面構造の形成メカニズム
In this regard, he said that in the particle of Naimi
この点に関して、彼はナイミの助詞で次のように述べた。
has its specific shape and number
特定の形状と数を持っています
Call this Magic Class
このマジッククラスを呼び出します
This is a very strange group of people
これはとても奇妙な人々のグループです
This is the basic research
これが基礎研究です
It has also received a lot of affirmation
こちらも多くの反響をいただいております
For example, this domestic outstanding talent talks about doing
たとえば、この国内の優秀な人材は次のように語っています。
Youyang Technology
ヨウヤンテクノロジー
I want to do a meeting of the Chinese American Physical Society
中国系アメリカ人物理学会の会合を開きたいです
American Physical Society Meetings, etc.
アメリカ物理学会総会など
What about the second research direction?
2番目の研究の方向性についてはどうでしょうか？
Is the material resistant to this result of imitation
この模倣の結果に対して材料は耐性がありますか?
Especially in this Yangji Yanghua
特にこの楊吉楊華では
Anti-fear materials in Yang Ji's Yanghua
Yang Ji の Yanghua の抗恐怖材料
Then this and this and these two
それからこれとこれとこの二つ
The second one is related to what I'm going to talk about today.
2 つ目は、今日お話しすることに関連します。
After glutinous rice is afraid of moving materials
もち米は材料を動かすのが怖いので、
can turn some metals into some
ある金属をあるものに変えることができる
That neat arrangement
そのきちんとしたアレンジメントは
Then use this to do the next step with this and use
次に、これを使用して次のステップを実行し、使用します
That part of the research results
研究結果のその部分
Also received a number of awards
数々の賞も受賞
Like the Executive Yuan Science and Technology Contribution Award
行政院科学技術貢献賞のようなもの
The Ministry of Economic Affairs' Difficult Technology Industry Gold and Silver Awards, etc.
経済部難度技術産業金賞、銀賞など
In addition to his research
彼の研究に加えて
Also contribute to academic administration, which is what we call service academic sociology
学術行政、いわゆるサービス学術社会学にも貢献します
He used to be a senior member of the National Science Department of Physics
彼はかつて国立科学物理学科の上級メンバーでした。
There are also two directors of the hospital who broke up with the hospital, etc.
この病院と決別した院長も２名いるなど。
The topic he talked about today is very interesting
彼が今日話した話題はとても興味深いです
Help us listen to the sound from bacteria with Laimi Optical Art
ライミ オプティカル アートでバクテリアの音を聞くのに協力してください
Our warm applause welcomes Laimi Optical Science
ライミ光学科学を歓迎する温かい拍手
Thank you, President Peng, for the invitation
彭社長、ご招待ありがとうございます
Thank you very much for the long introduction
長い前置き、本当にありがとうございました
I speak on many occasions
多くの機会に話します
No one has ever told so much about my not-so-honorable past
私のあまり名誉ではない過去について、これほど詳しく語った人は誰もいない
Before I came here today, I was actually very, very cautious
今日ここに来る前、私は実はとてもとても慎重でした
Because I probably told you that if you want to give such a speech, you must be legendary.
なぜなら、そのようなスピーチをしたいなら、伝説的なふりをしなければならない、と私はおそらくあなたに言ったからです。
tie
タイ
so my tie is here and my suit is here
だから私のネクタイはここにあり、私のスーツはここにあります
everyone to see the proof
みんなその証拠を見てください
After a few minutes, it still looks like this
数分経ってもこんな感じです
Then when I came in, I saw the curator Angel wearing this
それで私が入ったとき、学芸員のエンジェルがこれを着ているのを見ました
I'll just take him off and leave him here like this
私は彼を外して、このままここに残しておきます
I'm really, really honored today
今日は本当に本当に光栄です
I have such an opportunity to talk to you
あなたと話す機会があります
Borrowing this night, everyone should be watching that
今夜をお借りして、みんなも観てね
Is it time to turn around or something?
そろそろ方向転換の時期か何かでしょうか？
come here everyone
みんなここに来て
Let's talk about some science
科学について話しましょう
interesting things above
上記の興味深いもの
That just left the stage and mentioned to me
それはちょうどステージを去り、私に言いました
This time should be reserved a little more for the following questions, which should be more exciting
今回は、次の質問のためにもう少し時間を取っておき、より刺激的な質問をする必要があります。
so i'm going to talk
だから話します
20 minutes to fix it
直すのに20分
That
それか
because I saw
見たから
Because there are some colleagues in there who are experts
専門家である同僚もいますので
Because I'm actually a person who doesn't understand biology at all.
というのは、私は実は生物学を全く理解していない人間なのです。
Then I suddenly talk about video here
さて、ここで突然ビデオの話をします
It's actually something that scares me a little.
実はちょっと怖いことなんです。
But like these two pictures
でも、この2枚の写真のように、
What I see here are bacteria, red snowballs, and rice-resistant liquid.
ここで見られるのは、バクテリア、赤い雪玉、そして耐米性液体です。
I will introduce you step by step
順を追ってご紹介していきます
I hope that the youngest kid who is doing this can understand what I say
これをやっている最年少の子供が私の言うことを理解できることを願っています
Then I'll go ahead and talk about it
それから先に進んでそれについて話します
but good
でも良い
Before I talk about it, I want to introduce what is the original branch cable
その話をする前に、オリジナル分岐ケーブルとは何なのかを紹介したいと思います。
Because I am in this original branch
私はこの元のブランチにいるので
Everyone has heard it, but they don't know what the original branch cable is
誰もが聞いたことはあるが、オリジナルの分岐ケーブルが何なのかは知らない
This word will really disappear
この言葉は本当に消えてしまう
There is still a level above
まだ上のレベルがあります
its first half is also missing
前半も抜けてる
this place
この場所
The reason lies in
その理由は、
National Taiwan University campus
国立台湾大学キャンパス
It is not the original separate cable
純正のセパレートケーブルではありません
This is very important, because once there was an English translation and then it came back and translated the original content for us.
これは非常に重要です。なぜなら、一度英語の翻訳があった後、英語の翻訳が戻ってきて、元のコンテンツが翻訳されるからです。
That is to say, it is the history of the original division, which is the original division.
つまり、本来の部門である本来の部門の歴史です。
I want to explain to you first
最初に説明したいと思います
Yuan Tianchun is in the Zhengdong room of the National Taiwan University campus
袁天春さんは国立台湾大学キャンパスの正東室にいる
Later that year
その年の後半に
Dean Peng's Department of Chemistry at National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学の鵬学部長の化学科
Take down the old building
古い建物を取り壊す
let's settle there
そこに定住しましょう
Because Dr. Yuan Ze
袁澤博士だから
When Academician Yuan Ze was teaching at Bote University
学者の袁澤氏がボテ大学で教えていた頃
He came back to promote in Taiwan
彼は台湾でプロモーションするために戻ってきました
Hope to establish the research of atomic and molecular science
原子分子科学の研究を確立したい
Atoms and molecules are not originally separated
原子と分子はもともと分離されていない
in this way
この上
The study of atoms and molecules
原子と分子の研究
Why set up in Central Research
セントラルリサーチを設置する理由
actually you talk about it
実際にあなたはそれについて話します
Atoms are talking about physics
原子は物理学について話している
Molecules talk about chemistry
分子が化学を語る
So the original branch is actually
したがって、元のブランチは実際には
Institute of Physical Chemistry in Central Research Institute
中央研究所物理化学研究所
That is, we have two
つまり、2つあります
big brother or big sister
お兄さんまたはお姉さん
sandwiched here
ここに挟まれて
we're going in the canyon
私たちは峡谷に行きます
the whole survival place
生存場所全体
was sent to National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学に派遣されました
So it looks like it was originally separated.
ということで、元々は別物だったようです。
The first point is inside the campus of National Taiwan University
最初のポイントは国立台湾大学のキャンパス内です
It is on the small and medium East Road in their Taiwan University campus
台湾大学キャンパスの中小東路にあります
National Taiwan University Tourism Bureau
国立台湾大学観光局
If you go to the National Taiwan University campus
国立台湾大学のキャンパスに行くなら
We have a National Taiwan University campus that has become very beautiful now
国立台湾大学のキャンパスがとても綺麗になりました
It's worth seeing
見る価値がある
has a nice seat
素敵な席があります
In fact, there are many scenery at night
実は夜景もたくさんあるんです
It's all worth sharing with you
それはすべてあなたと共有する価値があります
Then you'll see a landmark over there
すると向こうにランドマークが見えてきます
There is a sculpture beside the game board
ゲームボードの横に彫刻があります
The name of this sculpture is Dot
この彫刻の名前はドットです
a chance to wait if someone asks me
誰かが私に尋ねたら待つチャンス
I'm explaining to you what I call a point
私がポイントと呼ぶものを説明しています
it's me
それは私です
A sculpture I raised for fundraising when I was in office
在職中に募金のために集めた彫刻
I think it is the most beautiful sculpture on the campus of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学のキャンパス内で最も美しい彫刻だと思います
is my biggest
私の最大のものです
The greatest contribution to this artifact
このアーティファクトへの最大の貢献
so i have to tell
だから言わなければなりません
This matter welcomes the young friends here to go there to talk about love
この問題は、愛について語り合うためにここにいる若い友人たちを歓迎します
Then go there to take wedding photos
それから結婚式の写真を撮りに行きます
This is my artistic wish
これが私の芸術的な願いです
Then my current director is Professor Zhou Meiying
さて、私の現在の院長は周美英教授です。
see you next time
次回会いましょう
In fact, a very stable theoretical physicist
実際、非常に安定した理論物理学者
he was originally in america
彼はもともとアメリカにいた
Chair of Georgia Tech's Department of Physics
ジョージア工科大学物理学科長
After the end of the five-year tenure of the department chair
学部長の5年間の任期終了後
He'll come back and pick me up
彼は戻ってきて私を迎えに来るだろう
Become Academia Sinica
中央研究院になる
number one since the original
オリジナル以来ナンバーワン
Director of your tree pear group
あなたの木梨グループのディレクター
is a founder
創設者です
just tell you
ただ教えてください
Heritage water has one great benefit
ヘリテージウォーターには大きな利点が 1 つあります
Heritage Water Does Not Discriminate
ヘリテージウォーターは差別をしません
is also very important
も非常に重要です
Our director is also this year
今年も弊社ディレクターが就任
very important one
とても大切なもの
She is an outstanding female scientist in Taiwan
彼女は台湾の優れた女性科学者です
Then this year's Taiwan female outstanding scientist
それでは今年の台湾の女性優秀科学者
so i stop here
だから私はここでやめます
That is, when the advertising time of the original committee is over
つまり、本来のコミティアの宣伝時間が終了した時点で
Aim does not want to be in this young friend
目的はこの若い友人にいたくない
I have the opportunity to go to the original commission to fall in love
私は恋に落ちるために元のコミッションに行く機会があります
in this way
この上
good
良い
Then what I'm going to talk about today
それでは今日は何を話そうかというと、
Just now the vice president has read
たった今、副大統領が読みました
I won't talk about it in particular
特に話さないけど
I hope to take this opportunity to convey a lot to you
この機会にたくさんのことをお伝えできればと思います
In fact, it is very unfamiliar to the general public.
実は一般の人にはあまり馴染みのないものなのです。
For example, when I heard Lai Nv
たとえば、Lai Nv を聞いたとき
Some people say that Lai Nv still has sex with Charity Girl
ライ・ヌヴは今でもチャリティー・ガールとセックスをしているという人もいる
Or it's not the same in the female tour group or something like that
それとも女性のツアーグループとかそういうのは違うのかな
that optical technology
その光学技術
then listen to the sound of bacteria
それからバクテリアの音を聞いてください
My original version had no parentheses
私の元のバージョンには括弧がありませんでした
Then I thought it was dangerous
そしたら危ないと思った
Because there are experts out there
専門家がいるから
Wait a minute to get out by my co-workers
同僚が出てくるまでちょっと待ってください
Fix it again and say you are cheating on this and that
もう一度修正して、あれこれズルしていると言う
It's not right to ride a cheater
詐欺師に乗るのは正しくない
So I just bracket it like this
だから私はこのように括弧で囲むだけです
That's a laser light over here.
あれはレーザー光線です。
and then after passing through a bacterium
そして細菌を通過した後
Then this bacterium is
そうすると、この細菌は、
The fungus shells are attached to a Lai's silver array
キノコの殻はライの銀アレイに取り付けられています
Then you this is an aperture laser light
では、これは絞りレーザー光です
After photographing and passing through
写真を撮って通過した後
And then that laser light comes in
そしてレーザー光が入ってくる
is a green light
緑色の信号です
go out and become a
外に出て、なる
Turn into a shade, turn into yellow light and go out
日陰になって黄色の光になって外へ出て行こう
Then we go to detect that light change
次に、その光の変化を検出します
then i can tell you
それなら教えてあげるよ
In fact, who is this matter with?
実際、この問題は誰に関係しているのでしょうか？
the sound is very close
音がとても近い
We rely on measurements like this
私たちはこのような測定値に依存しています
Another picture is
別の写真は
Similarly this array above
同様に、上のこの配列も
I
私
After laying a layer of eons of people
何年にもわたって人々の層を築いた後、
above this array
この配列は上にあります
become easier to catch bacteria
細菌がつきやすくなる
we catch germs
私たちは細菌を捕まえます
that blood cell ignores it
その血球はそれを無視します
Then catch the bacteria from the blood
そして、血液中の細菌を捕らえます。
come to listen
聞きに来てください
sound from bacteria
細菌から出る音
if everyone knew
みんなが知っていたら
like you listen to an instrument
楽器を聴くように
If you can hear the quality of that instrument
その楽器の良さが聞こえたら
you can probably guess
おそらく推測できるでしょう
Four or Five Cello or Violin
4～5人のチェロまたはヴァイオリン
the same you can probably guess
あなたもおそらく推測できると同じです
what bacteria
何の細菌
what about these voices
これらの声はどうですか
yes there is some help
はい、いくつかの助けがあります
so this is what i've said
だからこれが私が言ったことです
so let's start asking questions now
それでは、今から質問を始めましょう
Can
できる
OK
OK
then i think
それから私は思います
it's more purposeful than
それよりも目的があります
Let's talk about Laimi first, okay?
まずはライミについて話しましょう。
Let's explain Raimi
ライミについて説明しましょう
we are all used to
私たちは皆慣れています
everyone is used to
誰もが慣れています
what everyone saw
みんなが見たもの
probably all
おそらく全部
It's a tendency, that is, a meter creature
それは傾向です、それはメートルの生き物です
This little friend is a daughter, she looked like this when she was a child
この小さな友達は娘です、子供の頃はこんな感じでした
his sister is chasing him
彼の妹が彼を追いかけている
His height is one meter
彼の身長は1メートルです
I call everyone Yimi
私はみんなをイミと呼んでいます
We are one-meter creatures, our world is one-meter creatures
私たちは1メートルの生き物、私たちの世界は1メートルの生き物
Then inserting three orders of magnitude at once is an ant
それなら一度に3桁入れるのもアリ
about a micron of a mimi
ミミの約1ミクロン
Insert another number, your one million times is the protagonist
別の数量を挿入してください、あなたの 100 万回が主役です
Feelings from Dachang
大昌からの気持ち
When inserting another order of magnitude
別の桁を挿入する場合
Another three orders of magnitude, when you go down a thousand times
さらに 3 桁、1,000 回下がると
From this point to this side is Ichina you
ここからこちら側まではイチナ君
There are only four atoms in total
原子は全部で4つしかない
This is in my lab, 1998
これは私の研究室にあります、1998年
is a photo of a strange atomic cluster seen for the first time
初めて見た奇妙な原子団の写真です
This resolution photo means
この解像度の写真が意味するのは、
This work is my first doctoral student
この作品は私にとって初めての博士課程の学生です
he does the best
彼は最善を尽くします
quickly gained a lot of recognition in the world
すぐに世界で多くの認知度を獲得しました
We are still doing a lot of research on that aspect
私たちはその点に関してまだ多くの研究を行っています
In fact, there is no holiday in our field
実際、私たちの業界には休日はありません
But that's where both of us are interested
でもそれが私たち二人の興味のあるところです
wait a minute i'm going to talk about the tools we grind
ちょっと待ってください、私たちが研磨するツールについて話します
We are actually interested in making atoms or molecules
私たちは実際に原子や分子を作ることに興味があります
But because I want to compete with the biotech people for a bite to eat
でもバイオテクノロジーの人たちと一口食べるために競争したいから
I had to study bacteria
細菌を研究しなければならなかった
It's actually a pretty sad story
実はかなり悲しい話なんです
Then let me explain the meaning of scale first.
それでは、まずスケールの意味について説明させていただきます。
Because every time I tell you this 1000 times
だってこれを1000回言うたびに
Most of that you don't actually feel
そのほとんどは実際には感じていない
And 1000 times you don't actually feel it
そして1000回は実際には感じられない
But today I want to talk very practical
しかし今日は非常に実践的な話をしたいと思います
As long as you know what is 1000 times
1000倍とは何かを知っていれば
Let's talk about 100 times first
まずは100回くらい話してみましょう
Where was my little girl last night?
昨日の夜、私の小さな女の子はどこにいたの？
She has become the tallest girl in the family
彼女は家族の中で一番背の高い女の子になりました
She is 160 cm tall
彼女の身長は160センチです
Then she yelled in the room
それから彼女は部屋で叫びました
see her as a cockroach
彼女をゴキブリのように見る
You must help me kill this cockroach
このゴキブリを殺すのを手伝ってください
Then my heart skipped a beat, why should I help you kill the cockroaches?
それから私の心臓は高鳴りました、なぜ私がゴキブリを殺すのを手伝わなければならないのですか？
Do you know the relationship between your height and the ratio of cockroaches
自分の身長とゴキブリの発生率の関係を知っていますか？
if you were a cockroach
もしあなたがゴキブリだったら
If you are a cockroach
あなたがゴキブリなら
what about this person
この人はどうですか
Humans are 1-0 tall
人間の身長は1-0です
Then you'll see that one day you're yelling over there
そうすれば、いつかあなたがあそこで叫んでいることがわかるでしょう
Just look at 101 and move him, and then 101 keeps yelling
101 を見て動かしてみると、101 は叫び続けます。
Hurry up and hit him, hit him?
急いで彼を殴って、彼を殴って？
Just a bunch of 101s running around on the street
路上を走り回る101の群れ
Let's say there are cockroaches, there are cockroaches, there are people
ゴキブリがいる、ゴキブリがいる、人がいるとしましょう
of course not
もちろん違います
but that's weird
でもそれは変だ
people are so strange
人々はとても奇妙です
you only see cockroaches
ゴキブリしか見えない
My wife stopped fighting when she saw the ants
妻はアリを見て喧嘩をやめた
That's 1000 times
それは1000回です
1000 times means that
1000回ということは、
You go to Seven Star Mountain
七星山へ行きます
Your Qixing Mountain suddenly retreated 30 kilometers away
あなたの七星山が突然 30 キロメートル離れたところに後退した
After taking the potion, I still screamed at you
薬を飲んだ後も私はあなたに向かって叫びました
Of course this is
もちろんこれは
It means that people actually have all the power behind you.
それは、人々が実際にあなたの後ろですべての力を持っていることを意味します。
that size feeling
そのサイズ感
Let me tell you what you feel about numbers
数字についてどう感じているか教えてください
really want to think about you
本当にあなたのことを考えたい
Twice already big giant
すでに二度大きな巨人
Like when you're twice your height walking in
自分の身長の2倍の身長で歩いてくるような
is very scary
とても怖いです
not to mention
言うまでもなく
so you are seen what kushra those geography
それで、あなたはそれらの地理が何であるかを見ています
Those Kushras have no sense
あのクシュラ達にはセンスがない
But one word is a thousand times
でも、ひとつの言葉は何千倍もある
The most exaggerated would be to say
最も誇張して言うと、
object
物体
is the earth
地球です
we are creatures on earth
私たちは地球上の生き物です
We are a million times smaller than Earth
私たちは地球の100万分の1です
That is to say, if you are lucky
つまり、運が良ければ
you just find a good zoom spot
良いズームスポットを見つけるだけです
As soon as you look, you happen to see a certain snail beach
見るとすぐに、あるカタツムリのビーチが見えます
It's nice to see some creatures that look like these things
こういう生き物が見られるのは嬉しいですね
just lay there like this
ただこのようにそこに横たわって
you put this at a certain point
あなたはこれをある時点に置きました
One point of flashlight disaster
懐中電灯災害のワンポイント
Then when magnified a million times
そして100万倍に拡大すると
you see these things
あなたはこれらのことを見ます
actually looks about the same
実際はほぼ同じに見えます
no difference
変わりはない
That's a million times faster
それは100万倍速いです
In other words, our relationship with the earth
つまり、私たちと地球との関係
The relationship between bacteria and us
細菌と私たちの関係
In fact, this size is just your name
実はこのサイズはあなたの名前だけなのです
same thing
同じこと
so now
だから今
There is a noun called human ball
人間ボールという名詞があります
an earth, yes
地球、はい
so you are human ball
だからあなたは人間ボールです
You and I are human balls
あなたと私は人間のボールです
finally that translation is very interesting
最後に、その翻訳は非常に興味深いです
if flipping the ball
ボールを弾く場合
people will laugh
人々は笑うだろう
But as long as there is a way to scrape it up
でもそれをかき集める方法がある限り
Then of course we have a lot of drama
もちろん、たくさんのドラマがあります
so let's see
それでは見てみましょう
drama is actually a
ドラマというのは実は
There are many creatures older than us
私たちよりも古い生き物がたくさんいます
Because this drama has a protagonist
このドラマには主人公がいるから
In this case, I think people in the body should not dare to say such things to me.
この場合、体内の人はあえてそんなことを言わなくてもいいと思います。
Because the earth was formed forty-five years ago
だって地球は45年前に誕生したのだから
about thirty or forty years ago
30年か40年ほど前
It turns out that the drama has already happened
ドラマはすでに起こっていることが判明
There must have been ancient dramas in those days
あの時代には古代のドラマがあったに違いない
There's a drama up here in the whole life
人生にはドラマがある
What we now see more often
私たちが今より頻繁に目にするようになったもの
Everyone has Gram and Young's bacteria
誰もがグラム菌とヤング菌を持っている
Variety of Grammy plays
グラミー賞のさまざまな演劇
Then with this time it has been
それから今回はこうなりました
Then we are actually descendants of animals and plants
そうすると、実は私たちは動物や植物の子孫なのです
Then our animals and plants lived about five to one billion years ago
その後、私たちの動物や植物は約50億年から10億年前に生息していました
that's not very attractive
それはあまり魅力的ではありません
Humans are very skimpy
人間はとても卑劣です
you only have four to eight million people
400万人から800万人しかいない
It is the prime quotient of the whole life
それは人生全体の素指数です
Many of us are juniors like this
私たちの多くはこのようなジュニアです
so amazing
本当に素晴らしい
This junior is super arrogant
この後輩は超傲慢だ
I feel like everything is centered on me
すべてが自分中心にあるような気がする
then you will look carefully
それからあなたは注意深く見るでしょう
I just told you about the human rights
先ほど人権についてお話しました
doing things
物事をする
will we die
私たちは死ぬでしょうか
is that we will not treat our bacteria
それは細菌を治療しないということです
kill us as soon as we hear germs
細菌を聞いたらすぐに私たちを殺してください
everyone is angry
みんな怒っている
I mean, bacteria are so dirty.
つまり、細菌はとても汚いのです。
You see he just went to wash his hands
彼はただ手を洗いに行っただけだ
The result is a sterilizer.
その結果が滅菌器です。
why is it like this everywhere
なぜどこでもこんなことになるのか
but you will see
しかし、あなたは見るでしょう
this guy these guys
この人、この人たち
motion against earth
地球に対する動き
In fact, with bacteria trying to kill this guy
実際、バクテリアがこの男を殺そうとしている
This thing seems to be similar
これも似たようなものですね
We're digging everywhere
私たちはどこでも掘っています
do it here
ここでやってください
It's you who made the atmosphere dirty
空気を汚したのはあなたです
and then why
そしてなぜ
Actually quite similar
実はかなり似ている
there's a lot worth it
価値はたくさんある
Let's all go and think about it
みんなで考えてみよう
why are we doing this
なぜ私たちはこれをやっているのか
Well that bacteria
さて、その細菌
kill that tree owner
その木の所有者を殺してください
but we didn't get it right it was us
でも正しく理解できなかったのは私たちだった
maybe it's possible to kill the earth
もしかしたら地球を滅ぼすことも可能かもしれない
it's also possible
それも可能です
So we should think about it
だから私たちはそれについて考えるべきです
how should i do this
これはどうすればいいですか
I highly recommend here
ここを強くお勧めします
this book is
この本は
Let me tell you about the one written by Lida Vice Church
リダ・ヴァイス・チャーチが書いた本についてお話しましょう。
very popular book
とても人気のある本
everyone go back
みんな戻って
don't read my profile
私のプロフィールを読まないでください
Just go back and buy a copy of The World of Bacteria
戻って『The World of Bacteria』を購入してください。
there are very very interesting
とてもとても興味深いものがあります
just don't say he has a lot of numbers
彼がたくさんの数字を持っているとは言わないでください
Then he asked what he wrote in the preface
それから彼は序文に何を書いたか尋ねました
because of his order to write such a book
そのような本を書くようにという彼の命令のせいで
It is the justice of hoping to return the bacteria
菌を返してもらいたいのが正義
so don't hear it again
だから二度と聞かないでください
I hope you after that speech
あのスピーチの後はよろしくお願いします
Stop having so many prejudices about bacteria
細菌についての偏見を持つのはやめましょう
don't have that inappropriate
そんな不適切なことはありません
racial contrarian
人種的反逆者
I think you are much more advanced than him
あなたは彼よりもはるかに進歩していると思います
Then the number of bacteria on our body
次に、私たちの体の細菌の数
You can estimate it probably
おそらく推定できます
100 megabytes that many in this episode
このエピソードでは 100 メガバイトが多すぎます
In fact his numbers
実際、彼の数字は
10 times more bacteria than our body
私たちの体の10倍の細菌
That is to say, if we decide to make an agreement with Confidence, we will play the game of democracy.
つまり、もし私たちが自信を持って合意を結ぶことに決めた場合、私たちは民主主義のゲームをプレイすることになります。
we vote we only lose
私たちは投票します、私たちは負けるだけです
because he's already 10 times bigger
もう10倍も大きくなったから
we are a minority
私たちは少数派です
we should immediately
私たちはすぐにそうすべきです
Our cells vote and lose
私たちの細胞は投票して負けます
it's an interesting number
興味深い数字です
There are about 1,000 kinds of beliefs in the human digestive system.
人間の消化器系には約 1,000 種類の信念があります。
I was there
私はそこにいた
Most of those numbers are mostly unknown to us.
それらの数字のほとんどは私たちにはほとんど知られていません。
none of us can cultivate
私たちの誰も栽培できない
we don't know each other
私たちはお互いを知りません
They're like saying a lot of life on Earth is in the wild
彼らは地球上の多くの生物が野生であると言っているようなものです
they all had a great time
彼らは皆素晴らしい時間を過ごしました
But he's fine if he doesn't go to Utah
でもユタに行かなくても大丈夫
You don't have to put him in the zoo to raise it, it will be very difficult
動物園に入れる必要はない、育てるのは非常に難しいだろう
There are not many animals that we can raise
飼育できる動物が少ない
the same bacteria on our body
私たちの体にいる細菌
This is what many of my bio colleagues have said
これは私の生物学上の同僚の多くが言っていることです
would agree with me
私に同意するだろう
the vast majority of these thousand species of bacteria
これら千種の細菌の大部分は、
In fact, we have no way to train him in the experiment
実際、実験で彼を訓練する方法はありません
so we don't know him
だから私たちは彼を知りません
That means
つまり、
It is more interesting to put mountain towels in the wild
山タオルを野生に置いたほうが面白いです
Raising a lot of broilers for you is actually what we will raise
あなたのためにたくさんのブロイラーを育てるのが実際に私たちが育てることです
But it's actually less interesting
でも実際はあまり面白くない
Also he mentioned some very interesting things
また、彼はいくつかの非常に興味深いことについても言及しました
And then bacteria actually have a love-hate relationship
そして細菌には実際に愛憎関係がある
They will also have liangjingxiang
liangjingxiang もあります
Because there is an act similar to marriage
結婚に類する行為があるので
Then they also have collective wear
それから集団着用もあります
Then there are also sacrifices to clamp me these actions
そして、私をこれらの行動に締め付けるための犠牲もあります
In fact, after reading this book, I thought
実はこの本を読んで思ったのですが、
Professor Xu is really very, very
徐先生は本当にとても、とても
very very storytelling
とてもとても物語性のある
write a quick
簡単に書いてください
I read in his preface that he seems to have finished the book in two months
彼の序文を読んだところ、彼はこの本を2か月で書き終えたらしい
I really admire him very much
私は彼を本当に尊敬しています
So it is highly recommended here
なのでここはかなりオススメです
you can leave now
今すぐ出発できます
Just read a book
ただ本を読んでください
why listen to me
なぜ私の話を聞いてください
good
良い
In addition, what I would recommend is to say
さらに、私がお勧めしたいのは、
You can read last July's issue of Science Journal
昨年のサイエンス ジャーナル 7 月号を読むことができます
Then there are two articles
続いて記事が2つあります
Then these two articles
それからこの2つの記事
I would recommend here is to say
ここで私がお勧めしたいのは、
one of these
これらのうちの 1 つ
That is to say, this is shared with the continuation
つまり、これは続きと共通です
Your kind of numbers are worth tasting
君のような数字は味わう価値がある
is why we know that there are about a thousand species of bacteria
約1000種の細菌が存在することがわかっているのはこのためです
In fact, it is because we are talking about how many genes there are in bacteria
実際、細菌にはどれだけの遺伝子があるのか​​について話すつもりだからです。
Not the number of genes that make our bodies like ours
私たちの体を私たちのように作るのは遺伝子の数ではありません
About 20,000 to 25,000
20,000～25,000程度
But our bacteria have 150 times more genes than us
しかし、私たちの細菌は私たちの150倍の遺伝子を持っています
That's the bacteria if we count it all as one organism
すべてを 1 つの生物として数えると、それが細菌です
Let it adjust the whole kind
全体の種類を調整しましょう
In total they give us a
合計すると、彼らは私たちに
That is, if the number of genes is reversed
つまり遺伝子の数が逆になると
We lost even more, right?
もっとひどい負け方をしたじゃないですか。
We just said ten and we lost
10と言っただけで負けた
And to use the numbers of genes
そして遺伝子の数を利用する
Then we lost very miserably.
その後、我々は非常に惨めな負けを喫した。
There's a very biological
非常に生物学的なものがあります
related to medicine
医学に関連したもの
In this article, there are also 1.0 in the Science generation.
この記事では、Science世代にも1.0があります。
Professor Tetger Kasmarion is mentioned here at the very beginning of his article
テトガー・カスマリオン教授については、彼の記事の冒頭で言及されています。
He said that our ability in genes
彼は、遺伝子における私たちの能力は、
It is the point of view that the system function is better
システム機能が良くなるという観点です
interested in living on us
私たちの生活に興味がある
Let our immune system function better
私たちの免疫システムがより良く機能するようにしましょう
Such a statement is the only view on traditional
このような声明は伝統的なものに関する唯一の見解です
Because when we hear bacteria we think
なぜなら、バクテリアと聞くと私たちはこう思うからです。
Bacteria are bad things
細菌は悪者です
It is best not to have bacteria in our seven bodies
私たちの7つの体に細菌が存在しないのが最善です
But now gradually the information
しかし、今では徐々に情報が
Gradually more and more clear trend
徐々に傾向が明確になってきました
is immunity
免疫力です
Missed a few words from this today
今日はこの中からいくつかの単語を見逃しました
is the driver of immune system function
免疫システム機能の原動力である
is a symbiotic relationship
共生関係です
i think you grow up
あなたは成長したと思います
without those bacteria
それらの細菌がなければ
Actually there are many things
実は色々あるんですよ
your life won't be very pleasant
あなたの人生はあまり楽しくないでしょう
If there were no bacteria on earth
もし地球上にバクテリアが存在しなかったら
there are too many things
ものが多すぎる
Including whether you drink alcohol
お酒を飲むかどうかも含めて
or any of these things
またはこれらのことのいずれか
There are no bacteria, everyone can't do it
細菌は存在しない、誰もができるわけではない
too much fermentation
発酵しすぎ
These things are done by bacteria
こういったことは細菌によって行われます
In fact, bacteria are one of the best
実際、細菌は最も優れたものの1つです
Laimi made by myself
ライミは自分で作りました
Raimi's robot
ライミのロボット
Then he will repeat himself
それから彼は同じことを繰り返すでしょう
and then do something for you
そしてあなたのために何かをしてください
So take these loose
だからこれらを解放してください
The Laimi machine that lives with you
あなたとともに生きるライミマシン
is bacteria
細菌です
this is bacteria
これは細菌です
Then if those who are dependent on our civilization
もし我々の文明に依存している人々が
you look carefully
あなたは注意深く見ています
There are various types of bacteria in our gut
私たちの腸内にはさまざまな種類の細菌が存在しています
then on our skin
それから私たちの肌に
every place
どこでも
In fact, when we come out of the mother's birth canal
実際、私たちが母親の産道から出るとき、
from that moment
その瞬間から
We start with a bunch of bacterial denominators
一連の細菌の分母から始めます
Then he'll be on you when he's certified
そうすれば、彼は認定されたらあなたに協力してくれるでしょう
repeated to many children
多くの子供たちに繰り返しました
Maybe now there might be some evidence telling you that
もしかしたら今、それを物語る証拠が出てくるかもしれない
If you're not well inside your bowels
腸内の状態が良くない場合
There is a time when a bacterial phase is wrong
細菌の段階が間違っている場合がある
or whatever you are getting older
またはあなたが年をとったものは何でも
your bacteria
あなたの細菌
Then there is a vision in the body
すると身体の中にビジョンが生まれる
Then there is a bacterial phase in the gut
その後、腸内には細菌相が存在します
Because the bacterial phase is when the beginning is wrong
細菌期は始まりが間違っているときだから
your life will be out of balance
あなたの人生はバランスを崩すでしょう
Then this moving relationship will be messed up
そうなるとこの感動的な関係はめちゃくちゃになってしまう
You won't be happier when you break
壊れても幸せにはなれない
So the best way is to
したがって、最良の方法は次のとおりです
You have to find a way to talk to your fellow bacteria
仲間のバクテリアと会話する方法を見つけなければなりません
Get along well and live in peace with everyone, and have a better life
仲良く、みんなで平和に、より良い人生を送りましょう
I think I should agree with Xu Minda's textbook after I explained it like this
このように説明すると、徐敏達の教科書に同意する必要があると思います。
He wants us to pay back a bacterium
彼は私たちにバクテリアを返済してほしいと望んでいます
Another article talks about so-called probiotics
別の記事では、いわゆるプロバイオティクスについて説明しています
I was supposed to bring a bottle or two with me today
今日はボトルを1〜2本持っていくつもりだった
Let me tell you that when I drink one or two bottles in one gulp
言っておきますが、ボトルを1本か2本一気に飲むと、
I will take the population of the whole earth by a dozen
地球全体の人口を12に当てはめると
It was the confidence of dozens of people who drank it all in one gulp
一気飲みした数十人の自信作でした
Is that so?
そうですか？
Listen and see if there is a bottle or two
聞いて、ボトルが 1 ～ 2 個あるかどうかを確認してください
Then his size is as big as the earth came over
それから彼のサイズは地球がやって来たのと同じくらい大きいです
Then drink all the people on our earth in one gulp
それから地球上のすべての人々を一口で飲みます
It's actually quite scary for bacteria.
実は細菌にとってはかなり怖いことなのです。
right don't you think
そうですよね
Only sixty-one people disappeared.
行方不明者はわずか61人だった。
ok then we're going to start talking
わかりました、それでは話を始めます
what is the sound of bacteria
細菌の音は何ですか
I'm really not satisfied with this word
この言葉には本当に納得できない
What is the difference between the sounds played by Ma Youyou and bacteria?
馬友佑が奏でる音と細菌の違いは何でしょうか？
we know
私たちは知っています
What is Ma You playing?
マー・ユーは何を演奏していますか?
Everyone knows that Ma Youyou plays with a big body
マ・ユヨウが大きな体でプレーすることは誰もが知っています
This photo is really Ma Youyou
この写真は本当に馬友佑です
Yes, but could it really be Ma Youyou?
はい、しかしそれは本当に馬友佑でしょうか？
OK
OK
This is an ad for Ma Youyou's concert
これは馬友佑さんのコンサートの広告です
That
それか
The biggest difference between Ma Youyou and bacteria
馬友佑と細菌の最大の違い
It's about talking about the plan
計画について話すことです
just a million times worse
100万倍悪い
Let's talk about sound
音について話しましょう
so i'm going to tell you
だから私はあなたに言います
its difference is
その違いは
Where is the most important place
一番大切な場所はどこですか
Then it's a tone
それからトーンです
shake this thing over there
あそこでこれを振ってください
Then this shock and Ma Youyou's love sound pull the shock
そして、この衝撃とマ・ヨウヨウの愛の音が衝撃を引きます
It's actually very similar
実はとてもよく似ているんです
It's just that we can't hear the vibration
ただ振動が聞こえないだけです
But the voice of Ma Youyou
でも馬友佑の声は
listen 'cause i can't hear
聞こえないから聞いて
Now of course I can ask one
もちろん、一つ質問してみます
One is Ma Youyou's bacteria
一つは馬友佑菌です
Natara's big body
ナタラの大きな体
should
したほうがいい
where to put it frequently
よくどこに置くか
Just for the kids over there
そこにいる子供たちだけに
kid over there
そこの子供
I will ask today's exam questions
今日の試験問題を出題します
They didn't pass the flying mention
彼らはフライングメンションを通過しませんでした
don't go home like this
このまま家に帰らないでください
This bacterium Ma Yoyo reminds everyone
この細菌、マ・ヨーヨは皆に思い出させます。
May I ask the big theme song played by this bacteria
この菌が奏でる大きなテーマソングを聞いてもいいですか？
where is its comment dafabe
そのコメントはどこですか
I'm about to start talking a little bit
これから少しずつ話し始めます
Because I actually study
実際に勉強しているので、
Also very interested in music
音楽にもとても興味があります
so let me explain
それで説明しましょう
Everyone in Taiwan is playing the piano at home
台湾ではみんな家でピアノを弾いています
what's up with this math
この計算はどうなっているのですか
What is written on the piano is
ピアノに書いてあるのは、
That precious man you call it LAL
その大切な人をあなたはLALと呼びます
This standard IWC standard tone
この定番のIWCスタンダードトーン
maybe 440
たぶん440
Everyone has heard of A440
A440については誰もが聞いたことがあるでしょう
A440 means
A440 の意味
Your ears are covered with air like this
耳はこうやって空気で覆われている
When pressing 444 times per second
1秒間に444回押した場合
you hear the sound
音が聞こえます
If there is absolute pitch
絶対音感があるなら
You'll say that's LAL
あなたはそれがLALだと言うでしょう
This is what LAL on the piano means
これがピアノのLALの意味です
there was a very important musical discovery
非常に重要な音楽的発見がありました
I think it's a very important discovery
とても重要な発見だと思います
The meaning of my pronunciation of this matter is
この件についての私の発音の意味は、
The previous one, the high-pitched one, the rate is lower than that
前の、高音のもの、それよりもレートが低い
double, 800%
2倍、800%
Then how to divide it, find out that there is an interesting way to divide it
じゃあどうやって分けるか、面白い分け方があることを発見
The result of this division is to divide it into 12 semitones
この除算の結果は、12 の半音に分割されます。
Then the result is that the zero of 12 is 0, and then it is
その結果、12 のゼロは 0 となり、次のようになります。
Here is 1, 1 multiplied by the fold, and then this 1 is corrected
ここに 1 があり、1 に折り畳みを掛けて、この 1 を修正します。
Then we see it here, Masto
それならここで見ますよ、マスト
like this, go around
このように、回ってください
That's just right, if it's four semitones
半音4つあればちょうどいい
Well, I can't think that these two sounds are vibrato, which seems to be quite harmonious
まあ、この2つの音はビブラートとは思えませんが、かなり調和しているように見えます
So it will be more harmonious, then why is it more harmonious
だからもっと調和するだろう、それではなぜもっと調和するのか
It's because Douyin is so clean
ドゥインはとてもきれいだから
This number, very accurate calculation, the result is just about 5 to 4
この数字は非常に正確な計算で、結果はちょうど約 5 対 4 です。
Then you sound a lot, that is, there is a voice that is
すると、あなたはたくさん鳴ります、つまり、次のような声があります。
When I pressed five times, I pressed another four times, and it went smoothly.
5回押したら、さらに4回押したらスムーズにいきました。
What's more smooth is that the roots are collected, one is pressed twice, and the other is pressed three times
根元を集めて1回2回、もう1回3回押すとさらにスムーズです。
three to two
3対2
The smoothest and smoothest are four hundred and four and eight hundred and eight, exactly two pairs
最もスムーズとスムーズは 444 と 818、ちょうど 2 つのペアです
I hit it once, and you hit it twice. In this way, everyone feels that the chorus sound is very, very
私が1回叩いたらあなたが2回叩く、このように誰もがコーラスの音をとてもとても感じます。
Therefore, a series of phenomena
したがって、一連の現象は、
In fact, what they are talking about is a frequency, and what they are talking about is resonance.
実際、彼らが話しているのは周波数であり、彼らが話しているのは共鳴です。
or frequency these relationships
またはこれらの関係の頻度を増やす
So, today I hope to use such a method to tell you
ということで、今日はこんな方法でお伝えできればと思います
I’m in the manager, and I’m trying to tell everyone what’s going on with Xi Jinping’s voice
私はマネージャーで、習近平の声で何が起こっているのかをみんなに伝えようとしています
We're going back to ask him
戻って彼に聞いてみます
That Ma Yoyo's
あのマ・ヨーヨさん
please
お願いします
Why our ears are used to hearing, we all know that the frequency of our ears may be about
私たちの耳が聴覚に慣れている理由は、耳の周波数がおよそ
560 to 560 thousand or if someone doesn't want to listen, don't listen
56万から56万、あるいは聞きたくない人は聞かないでください
What's the best frequency?
ベストな頻度はどれくらいでしょうか？
There is actually a very simple reason for this
実はこれには非常に単純な理由があります
It's about our body
それは私たちの体のことです
Because the number of depths per second in the air is 330 meters per second
空気中の1秒あたりの深さの数は330メートル/秒であるため、
Everyone has heard of this junior high school
誰もがこの中学校のことを聞いたことがあるでしょう
if there is a thing
何かあれば
Its height and length have a resonance gun when the height reaches 1 meter
その高さと長さは1メートルに達すると共鳴砲を備えています
Its frequency is 330
その周波数は330です
It approaches 440 people every 30 meters
30メートルごとに440人に近づく
almost there
もうすぐそこです
So many people like the general policeman
一般の警察官が好きな人はたくさんいます
he is very comfortable
彼はとても快適です
It's not just ears
耳だけじゃないよ
his whole body is comfortable
彼の全身は快適です
Because he resonates with this resonant gun
この共鳴銃と共鳴するから
i'm done talking
話は終わりました
Because Toddler Ma and Tomorrow I are both 1 meter tall
幼児のマー君も明日の僕も身長が1メートルだから
The depth is about 330
奥行きは約330
So our ears are a natural evolutionary process
したがって、私たちの耳は自然な進化の過程です
Just 430
ちょうど430
Because this is about one or two hundred hertz on average
これは平均して約 100 ～ 200 ヘルツであるため、
The average amount needs to be in the range of Hertz to several thousand
平均量はヘルツから数千の範囲である必要があります
For example, when singing very high-pitched
たとえば、とても高い音で歌うとき、
He is going to put the resonance river on the small top of the head
彼は頭のてっぺんの小さな部分に共鳴川を置くつもりです
The younger he is, the higher the average is, the level of resonance in Zhenjiang
若ければ若いほど、鎮江市の共鳴度は平均的に高くなる
So what should the average be in the Xijing area?
では、西京エリアの平均値はいくらになるのでしょうか？
Did you raise your hand when you were a child?
子供の頃手を挙げましたか？
do you know the answer
あなたは答えを知っていますか
That's a million times more
それは100万倍です
Because Xijing's body size is a million times different from ours
西京の体の大きさは私たちの体とは100万倍も違うからです
So he's a million times taller on average
つまり彼の身長は平均で100万倍高い
So if Xijing plays his cello
それで、西京がチェロを弾いたら
Of course we can't hear
もちろん聞こえません
If this molecule is playing
この分子が再生している場合
When this molecule plays his cello
この分子がチェロを弾くとき
that would be another point
それは別のポイントになります
Because of the size of the molecule
分子の大きさから
It is ten to ten times worse than ours.
それは私たちのものよりも10倍から10倍悪いです。
So the average is higher again
それで平均はまた高くなる
That's why
それが理由です
So of course we can't hear
だから当然聞こえない
The voice of Wenzi and Molecule
ウェンジとモレキュールの声
We know that the principle is actually quite similar
実際にはかなり似ていることがわかります
We just figured out a way to secretly convert it
密かに変換する方法を見つけました
see if we can hear
聞こえるかどうか見てみましょう
This is how I think about bacteria from a human with atoms and molecules
これが私が細菌を人間の原子と分子から考える方法です
Bacteria, I can tell you very clearly this time
バクテリア、今度ははっきり言えます
What I call the sound of bacteria
私がバクテリアの音と呼ぶもの
It's actually a molecule from bacteria
実は細菌由来の分子です
how often they vibrate
どのくらいの頻度で振動するか
if i could hear
もし聞くことができたら
I know what molecules the bacteria emit
細菌がどのような分子を放出するのかを知っています
what kind of taste are those molecules
その分子はどんな味ですか
Or the concept of taste or sound is like this
あるいは味や音の概念はこんな感じ
ok
Ok
I speak a little fast
少し早口で話します
So if you want to know more details
それで、さらに詳しく知りたい場合は、
It's okay to interrupt me
邪魔しても大丈夫です
Okay, so we're going to see how to listen to this now.
さて、それではこれを聴く方法を見てみましょう。
This is the comparison I'm going to talk about today
今日お話しするのはこの比較です
Scientifically speaking, slowing down the valley of light sounds scary
光の谷の速度を落とすというのは科学的には恐ろしいことのように聞こえる
This is an Indian scientist who won the Nobel Prize in 1930, the Physics Prize
これは1930年にノーベル物理学賞を受賞したインドの科学者です
He is all Asian, the first Asian to win the Nobel Prize in Science
彼は全員がアジア人であり、アジア人として初めてノーベル科学賞を受賞した
so i was probably very young and i only got the nodel prize
だから私はおそらくとても若かったし、ノーデル賞しかもらえなかった
He did some very simple experiments himself in India, it sounds simple
彼はインドで非常に簡単な実験を自分で行いました、簡単そうに聞こえますが
Then published a magazine article in 1928 now called the shock number no one knows how much
その後、1928年に雑誌に発表された記事は、今ではどれだけのものなのか誰も知らない衝撃的な数字と呼ばれています
No one listened to it, no one didn’t know much about it, and there was an article about two or three years later that he won the Nobel Prize
誰もそれを聞かず、誰もそれについてあまり知りませんでしたが、約2、3年後に彼がノーベル賞を受賞したという記事がありました
He proved that resources are very simple, that is, he took some scales, and there was also a yellow light
彼はリソースが非常に単純であることを証明しました。つまり、彼はいくつかの秤を取り、黄色信号もありました
What can be green-yellow is also green-red, and it can be turned green
緑黄色になれるものは緑赤にもなり、緑色に変わることもあります
Then he proved one thing, that is, the light, the reason why the light sees different colors is because the screen is different
それから彼は一つのこと、それは光であることを証明しました。光が異なる色に見える理由は、スクリーンが異なるからです。
Don't say that hearing without red light is better
赤信号なしで聞こえる方が良いとは言わないでください
slower, lower
より遅く、より低く
The frequency of blue light is higher
ブルーライトの周波数が高い
The frequency of the blue light is just a little brighter.
ブルーライトの周波数が少しだけ明るくなります。
When I use a light mirror like this
こんなライトミラーを使うと
when the light mirror
ライトミラーのとき
There are very, very small light mirrors
とてもとても小さな光の鏡があります
it's time to come out
出てくる時間だよ
it will run out with a yellow light
黄色信号で消えてしまいます
Then it is clear about this matter
それではこの件に関しては明らかです
so it writes this article
それでこの記事を書いています
Then later when it was explained like this
その後、このように説明されたとき
why is this
どうしてこれなの
Because there are some molecules in it
分子が入っているので
After those molecules are excited by this light wave,
それらの分子がこの光波によって励起された後
Take that molecule as if dialing that emotion
その感情をダイヤルするかのように、その分子を手に取ってください
it vibrates
振動する
The frequency of the light at the time of the shock
衝撃時の光の周波数
just give it that frequency
その周波数を与えてください
Then the light only has its own frequency
その場合、光には独自の周波数しかありません
just lost a little bit
少しだけ負けた
so it was supposed to be aura
だからそれはオーラだったはずだ
then dropped a little bit
それから少し下がった
become light and run out
軽くなって走り出す
That's right, let's talk about this matter.
そうだ、この件について話しましょう。
So I tell many classmates every time I talk about this time
だから私は今回のことを話すたびに多くのクラスメートに話します
Everyone is a star
誰もがスターです
very angry
非常に怒っています
that person got one
あの人はそれを手に入れた
Just have a sun light, then the landscape mirror, and then take a few pieces of that rotten glass
太陽の光を当てて、次に風景鏡を当てて、それから腐ったガラスを数枚取ってください。
That's the proof that if Li Guang goes in and yellow light comes out, he will take the captain
それは、李広が入って黄色信号が出たら、彼がキャプテンを取るという証拠です
Why spend so much money on central research like this
なぜこのような中央研究に多額の資金を投じるのか
Then you have to explain this more profoundly, which probably means that it is called a
次に、これをより深く説明する必要があります。これは、おそらく、それが と呼ばれることを意味します。
For every molecule it actually has one like a resonance gun
分子ごとに、実際には共鳴銃のようなものが存在します。
then it starts to oscillate, it has a frequency it likes
それから振動し始めます、それは好みの周波数を持っています
When you send in a light, when you excite this thing
光を送るとき、これを興奮させるとき
This light will lose a little frequency, which happens to be
この光は周波数を少し失いますが、その周波数はたまたま
It likes this and that frequency, so as long as you see this, you will know
あれもこれも好きな周波数だからこれを見ればわかる
There is a musical instrument inside, and that musical instrument emits this frequency
中には楽器があり、その楽器はこの周波数を発しています。
Then this kind of thing can enable you to be called vibration spectrum
そうすれば、この種のことは振動スペクトルと呼ばれることができるようになります
Then we generally say that it just thinks about life.
そして、私たちは一般的に、それは人生についてだけ考えていると言います。
The frequency of direct life is very, very high, we can't even hear it
直接的な生命の周波数は非常に高く、私たちはそれを聞くことさえできません
What we're relying on is a laser light going in
私たちが頼りにしているのは、レーザー光が入ってくることです
Then let it come out and see how much it becomes, let's measure how much it becomes
じゃあ出してどれくらいになるか測ってみよう
How much will know the instrument that I measured
私が測定した機器はどれくらいわかるでしょうか
The instrument that I talked about a lot
たくさん話した楽器
its resonant frequency
その共振周波数
What is the vibration frequency it likes
好みの振動周波数は何ですか
This is the whole story
これがすべての話です
What about Mr. Raban?
ラバンさんはどうですか？
Just invented this Laban public servant, and there are also very fast
このラバン公務員を発明したばかりですが、非常に高速な公務員もいます。
So I get it in two or three years when I have a few
だから、いくつか持っていれば2、3年でそれを手に入れることができます。
what you dreamed of and got it at such a young age
あなたが夢見て、若くしてそれを手に入れたもの
If you want to look carefully
じっくり見たい場合は
Clearer young people are like
より明確な若者は次のようなものです
Let's say now this is a molecule
これが分子だとしましょう
This molecule probably
この分子はおそらく
Only the vice president can read it
副社長のみが読むことができます
Because I am your declaration
私はあなたの宣言だから
I don't even know what this molecule is called
この分子が何と呼ばれるのかさえわかりません
I just know it's some carbon, cream, green
カーボン、クリーム、グリーンだとわかっているだけ
Then this one looks like a flasher
それからこれはフラッシャーのように見えます
there is a vibration pattern
振動パターンがある
it opens like a flash
フラッシュのように開きます
Then there's one that likes to vibrate
それから、振動するのが好きな人もいます
So for each molecule it has
したがって、各分子について
it vibrates in different places
さまざまな場所で振動します
For example, this carbon heel
例えばこのカーボンヒール
Large, with carbon and oxygen
大きく、炭素と酸素を含む
it has one like this
このようなものがあります
It seems to be stretched like this
こんな感じで伸びるみたいです
each of these has a pattern
それぞれにパターンがあります
Then they all have their own vibration frequency
そして、それらはすべて独自の振動周波数を持っています
so which molecule is over there
それで、そこにあるのはどの分子ですか
Who wants to take his time
時間を取りたい人
You will measure several frequencies
いくつかの周波数を測定します
Yes, then you can analyze his different frequencies and you will know.
はい、それなら彼のさまざまな周波数を分析すればわかります。
use him as a fingerprint
彼を指紋として使う
you know what molecule
どの分子か知っていますか
like say you listen if your ears are really good
あなたの耳が本当に良いなら聞いてくださいと言っているようなもの
you listen to a good piano
あなたは良いピアノを聴きます
He or you listen to different instruments
彼またはあなたはさまざまな楽器を聴きます
You can tell what kind of instrument that is when you hear it
聴けば何の楽器か分かります
It's the same reason
これと同じです
So we borrow the concept
そこでコンセプトを拝借します
Treat that tone like a music garden
その音色を音楽の庭のように扱う
then we maybe
それなら私たちは多分
If you can hear the sound from bacteria
菌の音が聞こえたら
we can go back and say
戻って言うことができます
this may be some bacteria
これは何らかの細菌かもしれません
Or the more interesting thing I want to talk about is to say
あるいは、私が話したいのはもっと興味深いことです。
Then if this bacterium is attacked by others,
この細菌が他の細菌に攻撃されると、
For example, like being us
たとえば、私たちであるように
we call it the idiot antibiotic
私たちはそれを愚かな抗生物質と呼んでいます
From a bacterial point of view
細菌の観点から見ると
They were poisoned by us, right?
彼らは私たちによって毒を盛られたのですよね？
our miserable
私たちの惨めな
When everyone starts to kill
みんなが殺し始めると
defense of bacteria
細菌の防御
then he may emit molecules
そうすれば彼は分子を放出するかもしれない
or his skin is peeled off by you
さもなければ彼の皮はあなたによって剥がされてしまいます
or what these molecules
あるいはこれらの分子は何ですか
can we measure them
測ってもいいですか
at a vibrational frequency
振動周波数で
then we will know
そうすればわかります
change the voice of bacteria
細菌の声を変える
That's the story I'm going to tell today
それが今日私が話す話です
OK
OK
how to do this
これを行う方法
This frequency change is clearly coordinated in this place
この周波数の変化はここで明確に調整されています
that's not the case
そうではありません
If I notice here that there are some real experts
ここに本物の専門家がいることに気づいたら
they are fast asleep
彼らはぐっすり眠っています
heard here already said
ここですでに言ったことを聞いた
So my elementary school here already knows
だからここの小学校はもう知っている
i'm still here this
私はまだここにいます
It's okay if you start typing
入力を始めても大丈夫です
don't mind too much
あまり気にしないでください
Because I'm not talking about you
あなたのことを話しているわけではないから
good
良い
Ramek's light stock is actually very good
ラメックのライトストックは実際非常に良いです
What is the most useful Lame light stock?
最も有用なラメライトストックは何ですか?
in the quiz
クイズで
test
テスト
that
それか
would you be sir or
先生でしょうか、それとも
when your boyfriend proposes to you
彼氏があなたにプロポーズするとき
is it true
それは本当ですか
he took that diamond
彼はそのダイヤモンドを手に取りました
Then drill it for you like this
次に、このようにドリルします
I bought an 80 carat diamond to propose to you
あなたにプロポーズするために80カラットのダイヤモンドを買いました
Then you see how it is possible
そうすれば、それがどのように可能であるかがわかります
How is it possible for your salary
あなたの給料ではどうやってそれが可能ですか
how to check
確認方法
diamond
ダイヤモンド
No
いいえ
From a chemical point of view, even if it is the same as coal, it is charcoal
化学的には同じ石炭でも木炭です
If you go to propose to him and take a piece of charcoal, do you take one?
もし彼にプロポーズしに行って炭を持っていくとしたら、あなたは炭を持っていきますか？
My love is so real, then throw it in the fire and burn it
私の愛は本当に本物だから、火の中に投げ込んで燃やしてください
Then you took him a very shiny one, it may be a Soviet
それからあなたは彼に非常に光沢のあるものを持ってきました、それはソビエトのものかもしれません
what do you do then what do you do
何をしますか、それでは何をしますか
This chemistry is...
この化学反応は…
what is this? i don't know, it won't make a strange sound
これは何ですか? わかりません、変な音はしません
So this...
したがって、この...
How to test it, diamonds and Shi Nuo are the same
テスト方法、ダイヤモンドと石ヌオは同じです
It's all charcoal, or just plain...
全部炭だったり、ただの素だったり…。
There is a very simple way to talk about coal or something
石炭などについて話す非常に簡単な方法があります
It is the two big drawing boards, although their materials are all charcoal
大きな画板が2枚ありますが、素材は全て木炭です
But the arrangement of their atoms is different
しかし、それらの原子の配置は異なります
Then the arrangement is different, resulting in this action
すると配置が変わって、このような動作になります
The same material, when making a different feeling, its frequency is different
同じ素材でも、違う感触を生み出すとき、その周波数は同じではありません
so your boyfriend gave you a diamond
それであなたのボーイフレンドはあなたにダイヤモンドをくれました
you bring it is the first thing you take it
あなたがそれを持ってくるのはあなたが最初にそれを取ることです
Then you break the switch
それからスイッチを壊すんだ
once frequently wrong
一度は頻繁に間違える
OK
OK
That's it for next time
それは次回です
Actually we have some legislators
実は国会議員も何人かいます
When visiting our office
弊社事務所にお越しの際は
Let's just tell him we'll do this
彼にこれをやると伝えましょう
That's a female legislator
それは女性議員です
What we care most about is not whether our experiments are done well or not.
私たちが最も気にしているのは、実験がうまくいったかどうかではありません。
Is his diamond really like this?
彼のダイヤモンドは本当にこんなものなのでしょうか？
I want to say you can tell the name
名前を教えてほしいと言いたい
in this way
この上
Then of course you see
それならもちろんわかります
That's because it's very easy to use recently.
最近とても使いやすくなったからです。
Pull off the master's pull off
マスターのプルオフをプルオフ
Except for that
それ以外は
advanced is not really love me outside
上級者は外では私を本当に愛していない
and many other uses
その他多くの用途
various materials
さまざまな素材
you can hear his voice clearly
彼の声がはっきりと聞こえます
Then you can tell
そうすれば言えるよ
take him as a fingerprint
彼を指紋として採取する
You can use it for many tests
さまざまなテストに使用できます
but pull off the master
しかしマスターを引き離す
just after coming out
出てきた直後に
have similar grades
似たような成績を持っている
In the 1970s and 1980s
1970 年代と 1980 年代
actually very painful
実はとても痛い
Why
なぜ
There is an important reason to say
と言う重要な理由があります
Pull off the signal of the master
マスターの信号を取り出す
very very small
非常非常小
Everyone probably knows Fluorescent
蛍光灯は皆さんご存知かと思いますが、
Everyone in the fluorescent family has
蛍光家族の誰もが持っています
It looks like Li Yujun's
リー・ユジュンに似てる
In fact, there is a fluorescent light in the middle
実は真ん中に蛍光灯があります
Fluorescent itself is easy to light up
蛍光灯自体が点灯しやすい
that light
その光
I just told you about the Valley of Rahman Optics
先ほどラーマン光学の谷についてお話しました。
It's up to me to type a document to get in.
書類を入力して入るかどうかは私次第です。
Then it came out very hot
そしたらすごく暑くなってきました
very slightly hot
とても少し暑い
colored light
色のついた光
this thing to detect
これを検出するもの
often before
前によくある
I told the teacher who is Raman Optics Valley
私はラマン光学バレーの先生に話しました
ok then you can go
わかりました、それでは行ってもいいです
Go to the Yangliang thing
ヤンリャンの件に行く
and put it in
そしてそれを入れてください
Then the students will go skating on the mountain
それから生徒たちは山にスケートに行かなければなりません
The student will come back in three days
学生は3日後に戻ってきます
The Optics Valley just came out a little bit
光学の谷が少しだけ出てきました
Because that signal is very, very slightly hot
その信号は非常にわずかに熱いので
16 orders of magnitude worse than cloud light
雲の光よりも 16 桁悪い
I just said that the earth is 6 orders of magnitude different from us
先ほど地球は私たちとは6桁も違うと言ったばかりです
This Raman Optical Valley is 16 orders of magnitude different from Yunguang
このラマン光学谷は雲光とは16桁も違う
That difference of 10 orders of magnitude becomes
その10桁の差は、
It's so quiet I can't hear you at all
とても静かなので全く聞こえません
sounds like
のように聞こえる
I can hear you
私はあなたが聞こえる
Then it won't be talked about since people got it
そうすれば、人々がそれを理解したので、それは話題にならないでしょう
because it's useless
それは無駄だから
Because it is difficult to do this experiment
この実験は難しいので
in 1974
1974年に
there is a very
とてもあります
change of interest
興味の変化
at the University of West Germany
西ドイツ大学にて
especially professors they are doing
特に彼らがやっている教授たちは
accidental discovery
偶然の発見
you are going to detect
あなたは検出するつもりです
Here they do a
ここで彼らは、
molecular
分子
They're going to measure the molecule's short ad
彼らは分子の短い広告を測定する予定です
Turns out they put it in a
彼らはそれを
surface of a plume
噴煙の表面
The results of it
その結果
What about the surface of the feather mud?
羽毛泥の表面はどうでしょうか？
happens to be rough
たまたま荒れている
The results of it
その結果
Suddenly exploded by 1 million times
突然100万倍に爆発した
Exploded 1 million times
100万回爆発した
1 million times is to suddenly put feather mud
100万回はいきなり羽泥を入れること
down to the size of the earth
地球の大きさまで
super scary
超怖い
because it is on a surface
表面上にあるので
So this phenomenon is called
したがって、この現象はこう呼ばれます
surface enhancement
表面強化
shorten the ad
広告を短くする
Because people call it Surface Enhanced
人々はそれを Surface Enhanced と呼ぶからです
Abbreviated as Surge
サージと略される
wait a minute we'll see a lot of words
ちょっと待ってください、たくさんの単語が表示されます
S-E-R-S is such a thing
S-E-R-Sとはそういうものです
Everyone who suffers from the phenomenon of Surge
サージ現象に悩まされている皆様
wow many people
すごい人が多い
I thought this could find him
これで彼を見つけられると思った
why on earth
なぜ地球上で
Why can be enhanced a million times
なぜ100万回も強化できるのか
Some even enhanced to that meaning times
その意味に強化されたものもあります
or something
か何か
that's it
それでおしまい
At the beginning of 1970, the big circle was big
1970 年の初め、大きな円が大きくなりました
it's been 40 years
40年経ちました
I solemnly declare here
ここに厳かに宣言します
The most detailed reason
一番詳しい理由は
Why can it be enhanced to so much
なぜそこまで強化できるのか
From theory to experiment
理論から実験へ
issues that have not yet been fully resolved
まだ完全に解決されていない問題
This question is a
この質問は、
still a still ongoing party center
まだ進行中のパーティーセンター
Even if everything is as good as we are now
たとえすべてが今と同じように順調だったとしても
But that detail in that
しかし、その詳細は
so many male protagonists
男性主人公が多すぎる
I can't even talk here today
今日はここで話すことすらできない
but i want to tell you
でも、あなたに言いたいのです
The person who discovered this phenomenon
この現象を発見した人
Some people think they've been dreaming about him
彼のことを夢見ていたと思う人もいる
that should be in his lifetime
それは彼の生きているうちにあるはずだ
will get that to talk like this
このように話してもらいます
I think he probably doesn't have much hope
おそらく彼はあまり希望を持っていないのだと思います
that I know like this
私がこのように知っていること
that would be a very interesting phenomenon
それはとても興味深い現象でしょう
But I don't agree that a thing can be enhanced to a million to a billion times
しかし、私は物が100万倍から10億倍まで強化できるということに同意しません
something like this is a big deal
このようなことは大したことです
Just like when the money in your pocket suddenly increases by a billion times
ポケットの中のお金が突然10億倍になったときのように
you are very very excited like this
あなたはとてもとても興奮しています
That's certainly an interesting phenomenon
確かに面白い現象ですね
But it starts directly from the details
しかし、それは細部から直接始まります
It is the electromagnetic factory
電磁工場です
Because laser light is an electromagnetic factory
レーザー光は電磁工場だから
Then why is it like this
ではなぜこうなっているのか
And then what exactly is the molecule that is adsorbed on the surface of this silver
では、この銀の表面に吸着している分子は一体何なのでしょうか？
so what's under this arrangement
それで、この取り決めは何ですか
it will have such a large signal enhancement
非常に大きな信号増強が行われます
This is how the details of each film require lucky scientific research
このように、各映画の詳細には幸運な科学的研究が必要です
Then we have been doing it until now
それから今までそうしてきました
but i want to tell you again
でももう一度言いたいです
Although we don't fully understand its rationale
その理論的根拠は完全には理解できませんが、
But we can still use
しかし、まだ使用できます
It's like saying I don't understand what violin sentiment is all about
ヴァイオリンの感情が何なのか理解できないと言っているようなものだ
But it has to be about the fact that I can't play the violin
でもそれは私がヴァイオリンを弾けないという事実に違いない
is the same reason
同じ理由です
so it's for you
それはあなたのためです
but really
でも本当に
So from the most primitive principle, we still don't have a special understanding
つまり、最も原始的な原理から、私たちはまだ特別な理解を持っていません
Although we have about 80% or 90% understanding, it is already good
理解は8割か9割くらいですが、もういいです。
But those last few areas hopefully we can go on in my lifetime
でも、最後のいくつかの分野は、私が生きている間に続けられるといいのですが
This two-sided, this Laren light map, this phenomenon
この両面、このラーレン光マップ、この現象
In 1974, it was red for about ten years before it became a plated
1974年、メッキになるまで約10年間赤でした
Just because they can't go on
ただ続けられないからといって
that's great
それは素晴らしいことです
It's that they have probably changed their careers in those years.
それは、彼らはおそらくその年の間にキャリアを変えたということです。
By 1997
1997年までに
There is a scholar named Nie Shuning who went to the United States from mainland China
中国本土から米国に渡った聶順寧という学者がいる
Nie Shuning
聶順寧
This article he published in Science
彼がサイエンス誌に掲載したこの記事
This article has probably been cited 3,000 times so far
この記事はこれまでにおそらく 3,000 回引用されています
Because this is tantamount to the renaissance movement of surface-enhanced full-light maps
これは、表面強化フルライト マップのルネッサンス運動に等しいからです。
Thirty years later, I suddenly published this article again
30年後、突然この記事を再び公開しました
He did a very interesting experiment
彼はとても興味深い実験をしました
When I was just drawing with him
彼と一緒に絵を描いてたとき
We've got the rough surface when we're here today
今日来た時にはすでに表面が荒れていました
What happened after Ke Zhi appeared?
柯志登場後はどうなったのでしょうか？
Don't use this to corrode
腐食には使用しないでください
he's in trouble
彼は困っている
I don't know if I said it
私が言ったかどうかはわかりません
Let's just make some rice
ご飯を作ろう
particles of silver
銀の粒子
just hit one by one
一つずつ叩くだけ
and sprinkle it on the surface
そして表面にふりかける
then measure this
それからこれを測ってください
Enhance the signal of Optics Valley?
オプティクスバレーの信号を強化しますか?
Then he did it
それから彼はそれをやった
Then he took that Optics Valley
それから彼はその光学谷を占領しました
That's the one
それだ
It's just gold particles sprinkled on it.
そこに金の粒子が散りばめられているだけです。
and then what
それから何
He hit a light on it
彼はそれに光を当てた
Particle shot in
粒光打進去
Then I saw you talking about particle light shooting in
それからあなたが粒子光の発射について話しているのを見ました
The words of Raman Kwang
ラマン・クワン氏の言葉
yellow light running out
黄色のライトが切れる
That's either Raman light or it's reflected back
それはラマン光か反射されたかのどちらかです
It's the particles of light that go in and the particles of light come out, right?
光の粒子が入ってきて、光の粒子が出てくるんですよね？
Well, you can see this small picture
さて、この小さな写真を見てもらえば分かると思いますが、
Because most of it is grain light going in and grain light coming out
なぜなら、そのほとんどは入ってくる粒子の光と出てくる粒子の光だからです。
there are a lot of
がたくさんあります
Granules of Lamikin
ラミキンの顆粒
In the end, I saw two or three
結局２、３個見ました
yellowish
黄色っぽい
Then this article becomes a
すると、この記事は、
very very interesting discovery
とてもとても興味深い発見
So everyone thought
そこでみんなが思ったのが
That is, we tore 10,000 pieces
つまり、10,000個を破りました
that that that
それはそれは
This light source goes down and cries
この光源が落ちて泣く
Once we can, everyone will work hard to prop up the signal into a million times, and each person will share a hundred times
それができたら、全員が頑張って信号を100万回に引き上げ、一人一人が100回共有するでしょう。
It turns out that there are only three people who are actually working. What is the consciousness? Those three people are police officers.
実際に働いているのは3人だけだということが分かりましたが、どういう意識ですか?その3人は警察官です。
This phenomenon is called the discovery that even if the surface is enhanced and recovered
この現象を表面を強化・修復しても、
In the past 30 years, I didn’t know anything about it. There were some very, very HOT people in it.
過去30年間、私は何も知らなかったのですが、そこにはとてもとても熱い人たちがいました。
It is called HOTSBOT, which is a very hot hot zone, and it still contributes 5-60% of the real contribution
これは HOTSBOT と呼ばれ、非常にホットなホット ゾーンであり、実際の貢献度の 5 ～ 60% を占めています。
The other tens of thousands of people only contribute the other 5-60%
残りの数万人は残りの 5 ～ 60% のみを寄付しました
So this is called the concept of a very hot hot zone, which is the hot spot of HOTSBOT
これは非常にホットなホット ゾーンの概念と呼ばれるもので、HOTSBOT のホット スポットです。
That’s why I’m gradually starting to talk about what my research has to do with this matter.
そこで、私の研究がこの問題にどのような関係があるのか​​を少しずつ話し始めています。
I will comment here first, and talk about the original problem
最初にここにコメントして、元の問題について話します
I see that there are not many people who go to bed early
早く寝る人は少ないようですね
So I'm actually more and more confident
だから私は実際にますます自信を持っています
Teacher you just said that
先生、さっきそう言いましたね
440 that voice that pulls
440 引っ張るその声
Is his higher octave 888
彼の高いオクターブは 888 ですか
What about an octave lower?
1オクターブ低い場合はどうでしょうか？
an octave lower is that frequency
オクターブ低いのがその周波数です
This except 2
これは2を除いて
So he's a 2 speed
つまり彼は2スピードです
Then his contribution is to say
すると彼の貢献度は
why did you find this
なぜこれを見つけたのですか
if you can't cut it
切れないなら
i can't turn around
振り向くことができない
do you know
あなたは知っていますか
that's what i say
それが私の言ったことです
the thought of cutting it into 12 semitones
それを12半音に切るという考え
Then there is a semitone between the eight and the close
そして、8と近くの間には半音があります。
Then there is a semitone between C and D
CとDの間には半音があります
Total like this plus
合計はこのようにプラス
The result
結果
just so close
とても近い
There will be an extra charge
追加料金が発生します
There's also the matter of multi-tracking
マルチトラッキングの問題もあります
Then his ears heard
すると彼の耳は聞こえた
Well, I've actually met people with that kind of absolute pitch.
まあ、実際にそのような絶対音感を持つ人に出会ったことがあります。
they hate it
彼らはそれが嫌いです
because what he wants is
なぜなら彼が望んでいることは
I just said 3 to 2
さっき3対2って言ったけど
he wants to be like a mathematician
彼は数学者のようになりたいと思っています
Accurate 3 to 2, it can hear the difference
正確な 3 対 2、違いを聞き取ることができます
Just now I told you that it was 1.4987
今、1.4987だと言いましたね
If the ratio is 3 to 2, it is not 1.5.
比率が 3 対 2 の場合、それは 1.5 ではありません。
That's 1.4987, isn't it one thousandth of a difference?
それは1.4987です、1000分の1の差ではないでしょうか？
It's almost audible at all frequencies.
ほぼすべての周波数で聞こえます。
So if you listen, well I hear Acapella
だから聞いてみると、アカペラが聞こえるよ
Last night I went to the National Concert Hall was Akapela
昨日の夜国立音楽堂に行ったのはアカペラでした
Many masters there are real
そこにいる多くのマスターは本物です
when we get along very, very, very well
私たちがとても、とても、とても仲良くなったとき
Not the sounds on the piano
ピアノの音ではなく、
because I'm always 440
私はいつも440だから
I am not the frequency of 4401
私はこの周波数ではありません 4401
I am 4401.5, so any frequency is fine
私は4401.5なのでどの周波数でも大丈夫です
So these are selected
したがって、これらが選択されます
Once selected, the other sounds seem to be non-existent to you
一度選択すると、他の音は存在しないように見えます
But the sound of 4401 means of course
でも、4401の音は当然のことを意味します
Wait a minute, I'm finally going to broadcast the sound of that bacteria to you
ちょっと待って、いよいよあの菌の音を君に届けるよ
I say that because you are digitally generated
私がそう言うのは、あなたはデジタルで生成されたものだからです
So you want me to put a pattern
それでパターンを付けてほしいのですが
I'll wait until I play a 723 frequency for you to listen to
723 周波数を再生して聞いてもらうまで待ちます
OK
OK
there are other problems
他にも問題があります
If not
そうでない場合
It seems that everyone is still maintaining the status quo
まだみんな現状維持してるみたいだ
I'll just keep talking
ただ話し続けます
we just want to say
私たちはただ言いたいだけです
after some research
いくつかの研究の後
found that those hot spots
それらのホットスポットを発見しました
what is it actually
実際には何ですか
looks like
のように見える
you thought
あなたは考えた
here is a bright spot
ここは明るい場所です
It is because the optical display resolution is not enough
光学ディスプレイの解像度が十分ではないためです
really those hot spots
本当にホットスポット
It's actually two atoms of gold.
それは実際には2つの金の原子です。
it's very very close
とてもとても近いです
that in optical display
光学ディスプレイのそれ
These particles of gold that I'm going to talk about
これからお話しするこれらの金の粒子について
Size is 25 Nie Camp
サイズは25ニーキャンプです
I just forgot to mention one thing
ただ一つ言い忘れてました
What are we usually used to
私たちは普段何に慣れていますか
For example filter
たとえばフィルター
wavelength
波長
is the fluctuation of the wave
波のゆらぎです
Like the waves of the ocean the long way this wave goes
海の波のように、この波は遠くまで続く
The filter is about 550 or so
フィルターは550くらいかな
It is 550 Naiying
550内営です
So we're doing camping now
ということで今キャンプ中です
It's better than that wave
あの波よりはいいよ
10 times less frequent
頻度が10分の1に減る
or 20 times as small
または20倍小さい
so we make that light
だから私たちはその光を作ります
Just a little big beach to see
ちょっと大きなビーチが見えるだけ
The fluctuation of the wave of the ocean is one meter.
海の波の揺れは1メートルです。
When we reach the shore, if it is a sandy beach with accidental rocks
海岸に着いたら、それが偶然の岩のある砂浜なら
The person who accidentally stoned one by one fell
誤って石を投げた人が次々と倒れた
The waves hit the small stones by the sea
波が海辺の小さな石にぶつかる
Those little stones are using this metaphor
あの小さな石たちはこの比喩を使っている
These are the small stones that we are making at Nini Technology
私たちがNini Technologyで作っている小さな石たちです。
That wave hits like a light wave
その波は光の波のようにぶつかる
550 Nini is hit on a particle of tens of Nini
550ニニが数十ニニの粒子に当たる
is such a game
そんなゲームですか
Because our Naini technology has now advanced to
なぜなら、当社の Naini テクノロジーは現在、
It’s not ideal yet, but it’s already possible to be Shi Nai Ni
まだ理想的ではないけど、すでにShi Nai Niになれる
Well done here
ここでよくやった
Then we just have to find a way to agree
それなら同意する方法を見つければいいだけだ
Since it is like this
こんな感じなので
Are we going to be able to do a bunch of Nenny examples?
Nenny のサンプルをたくさん実行できるでしょうか?
Then they get very close
それから彼らはとても近づきます
So everyone is hot in the middle
だからみんな真ん中が熱いんです
In that case, wouldn't the signal be amplified even more?
その場合、信号はさらに増幅されるのではないか？
That's when I was a student in the master's class of the Physics Department of National Taiwan University with me.
それは私が国立台湾大学の物理学科の修士課程の学生として一緒だったときです。
gave advice
アドバイスをした
It's a long story because I've actually been doing this for almost a decade
実はこれを10年近くやっているので長い話になります
I'm not here to spend time telling stories
私は物語を語るために時間を費やすためにここにいるわけではありません
But this young man was very interesting, so he said yes
でも、この若者はとても興味深かったので、イエスと言いました。
We actually just happened to have a senior working on this material
実はたまたま先輩がこの教材に取り組んでいたのです
This material is here, many first-time students can do it by themselves when they go home.
この教材はここにあります。初めての生徒の多くは家に帰ってから自分で行うことができます。
This, everyone said that selling Mi Technology sounds very difficult
これは、Mi Technology を販売するのが非常に難しいと誰もが言います。
How to do Mimi Technology, in fact, it sounds very simple
Mimi Technologyのやり方、実はとても簡単そうに思えます
When you get home, go buy a battery
帰ったら電池買いに行こう
Then you make a little acid, then leave the acid or muddy acid
次に、少し酸を作り、酸または濁った酸を残します。
Or a little bit of acetic acid, which is safer
または少量の酢酸の方が安全です
So stainless steel, another piece of aluminum
つまり、ステンレス鋼、別のアルミニウム
Aluminum is usually at home, and the aluminum box puts it here
アルミニウムは通常家にあり、アルミニウムの箱はそれをここに置きます
Then add this battery here, then add it, and then it starts to clear
次に、このバッテリーをここに追加し、さらに追加すると、クリアが始まります
Then after taking the risk, you thought it would be difficult
リスクを取った後は難しいと思った
very expensive machine
非常に高価な機械
This is why everyone should support the central research
これが、誰もが中央研究をサポートする理由です
you have expensive machines
あなたは高価な機械を持っています
you can take this picture
この写真を撮ることができます
just become money
ただお金になるだけ
you didn't see say
あなたは言うのを見ていませんでした
it turns out that
それは判明しました
if there is not
ない場合
you see nothing happened to us
私たちには何も起こらなかったことがわかりますか
It's just a woman here
ここにいるのは女性だけです
but when you actually look
しかし実際に見てみると
It's actually full of holes like this
実はこんな穴だらけなんです
And this is completely spontaneous
そしてこれは完全に自発的なものです
when you don't need a car
車が必要ないとき
it is brought
それは持ち込まれます
and very interesting
そしてとても興味深い
This is a material given in the previous part
前編で紹介した資料です
That
それか
You see it's really just a hole
ほら、本当にただの穴だよ
keep it in
入れておいてください
it is this
これです
cut it all the way
ずっとカットして
it's really
それは本当に
The straight film is always put in like this
ストレートフィルムはいつもこうやって入れます
keep it in
入れておいてください
That
それか
its pipe is
そのパイプは
This is like a room tube
これはルームチューブのようなものです
But a whole row of chamber tubes
しかしチャンバーチューブの列全体
it keeps going in
それは入り続けます
this is the material
これが材料です
so
それで
there should be a way
方法があるはずです
OK
OK
Automatically
不重自動
I should not be...
そんなはずはないのですが…
they are...
彼らです...
have...
もつ...
yesterday no...
昨日はいや…
I'm going to listen to Cappeda
カペダを聞いてみます
There is a special sound maker like this
こんな特殊なサウンドメーカーもあるんですね
is good music
良い音楽です
music
音楽
I said you take this material
この資料を受け取ってくださいと言った
Then start going...
それから行き始めてください...
This is called...
これを...といいます。
Shock oxidation
衝撃酸化
This is called blow oxidation treatment
これをブロー酸化処理といいます
Oxidation of the blood vessel in the target
ターゲット内の血管の酸化
This way I will always...
そうすれば私はいつも...
go down
降りる
That sound doesn't need to be too audio
その音には多くのオーディオは必要ありません
Is this okay
これで大丈夫ですか
Can
できる
so it's because the sound
それは音のせいです
there's noise
騒音があります
now he is talking
今彼は話しています
or this
またはこれ
So in the end, there is a shortage of funds
結局資金不足になるんだよ
when i first came
初めて来たとき
some that really good one
本当に良いものもあります
Can't connect to a computer
コンピュータに接続できない
so wait a minute
だからちょっと待ってください
We relate donations later
寄付金は後日連絡します
that's the funniest thing to say
それは言うのが一番面白いことだ
listen up everyone
みんな聞いてよ
He will do this himself
彼はこれを自分でやります
A pipe goes down vertically
パイプが垂直に下がっていきます
This expression throughout the cycle
サイクル全体を通してこの表現
only you
あなただけ
only he is like this
彼だけがこんな感じだ
you smooth it out
あなたはそれを滑らかにします
So there are a lot of new bricks here.
ここには新しいレンガがたくさんあります。
anyway you have to smooth
とにかく滑らかにしなければなりません
And today we will put it
そして今日はそれを載せます
put it in the plug
プラグに差し込んでください
Then he'll grow in by himself like this
そうすれば彼はこのように一人で成長するでしょう
Then keep bricking in
その後もレンガ造りを続けてください
Then this brick goes in
それからこのレンガが入ります
brick into this
これにレンガを入れる
So this ratio
つまりこの比率は
This ratio is easily
この比率は簡単に
This is like a tunnel with this pipe
このパイプでトンネルのようなものです
The length of this tunnel is compared with this pipeline
このトンネルの長さをこのパイプラインと比較します
It is easy to do casually and it is longer than the snow mountain tunnel
気軽にできて雪山トンネルより長い
So when you go in, you can say that my current management environment is
ですから、入社してみると、私の現在の経営環境は次のとおりです。
Shimi is ready
シミは準備ができています
Then you need to get a 500 mic
それなら500マイクを買う必要がある
just wait for three days
3日間待ってください
And then it turns straight in and straight
そしてそれは真っ直ぐに曲がります
just keep turning in
ただ入り続けてください
just put it there
そこに置いてください
Then you're skiing again, just go skiing
それからまたスキー、スキーに行きましょう
do what you should be doing
やるべきことをやる
you are so sour
あなたはとても酸っぱいです
Just straight up help you do this later
後でこれを行うのを手伝ってください
That's a chemistry called itself
それはそれ自体が化学と呼ばれるものです
self organized
自己組織化された
a process of self-combination
自己結合のプロセス
that's more interesting like this
こっちのほうが面白いよ
If you
もし、あんたが
You find an acid that is sulfuric acid
硫酸という酸が見つかりました
Then you tell me that I should be Yang Jizu
それからあなたは私にヤン・ジズになるべきだと言いました
What is the voltage of a battery
バッテリーの電圧とは何ですか
How much did I spend a earth voltage on?
接地電圧にいくらかかりましたか?
It will find, that is to say, you go to different acids, called zero acid, salicylic acid
つまり、ゼロ酸、サリチル酸と呼ばれるさまざまな酸が見つかります。
One thing that will happen when they are in different pressure changes is
異なる圧力変化にさらされた場合に起こることの 1 つは、
Even if it is lined up here, it will be neatly arranged, horizontally
ここに並べても綺麗に横に並びます
As long as the rows are close to each other, like this one is well-behaved
この行のように行が互いに近い限り、行儀が良いです
Arranged like a grid, not like the one just now
先ほどとは違い、格子状に配置
The row here is not so good
ここの並びはあまり良くない
But in some acids, it selects its own row
ただし、一部の酸では独自の行を選択します
And it's very, very simple, you'll make this Naimi
それはとてもとても簡単です、あなたはこれを作ります、ナイミ
That is, you add the transformer voltage of each frame
つまり、各フレームの変圧器電圧を加算します。
The distance between the hole and the hole is only 2.5 meters
穴と穴の間の距離はわずか2.5メートルです
Which means you're going back home and it's easy to get that
つまり、家に帰ることになるので、それを手に入れるのは簡単です
You can buy a nine-panel battery with just one
9 パネルのバッテリーを 1 つだけで購入できます
Bring it, it's easy about 50 yuan, 100 yuan
持ってきてください、50元、100元くらいで簡単です
Then you take a little bit of acetic acid, or that
それから酢酸を少し摂取します。
that salicylic acid or something and then you put it in
サリチル酸か何かを入れてください
I probably wouldn't have acted like this back then
当時の私はおそらくこのような行動はしなかったでしょう
But not so well
でもあまり良くない
but the distance between their average openings
しかし、それらの平均開口部間の距離は
It also fits this relationship
この関係にも当てはまります
Then it's easy to get out of that country
そうすればその国から出るのは簡単だ
Or elementary school classmates did this
それとも小学校の同級生がやってたのか
Then take it to talk to their teacher
それからそれを持って先生に相談してください
I made a nanostructure
ナノ構造体を作りました
The nanostructures are only 25 nanometers apart
ナノ構造間の間隔はわずか 25 ナノメートルです
If you don't believe me, just go and see for yourself
私の言うことが信じられないなら、行って自分の目で確かめてください
Then the teacher said
すると先生はこう言いました
Then I'm going to buy an electronic behavior gold like this
じゃあ、こんな感じの電子行動ゴールドを買おうと思います
According to the price to be able to 5 million is too low
価格によると500万は低すぎる
But now it doesn't have to
しかし今はその必要はありません
Send it to a company to work with our company
当社と提携する企業に送信してください
They can help you quickly
彼らはすぐに助けてくれます
Just charge you two thousand yuan
2000元だけ請求してください
OK
OK
so what
だから何
Because I actually play with this material
実際にこの素材で遊んでいますので
not for this
このためではない
I have been doing research on this material since 20...
私は20年からこの材料について研究を続けてきました...
that...
それか...
It should be said that in 2011
2011年にそう言うべきです
I will publish the first article
最初の記事を公開します
i won't talk about that detail
その詳細については話しません
The whole idea is this
全体のアイデアはこれです
because we have a very accurate
私たちは非常に正確な情報を持っているので、
This self-owned land gives us all the materials
この自己所有の土地は私たちにすべての資材を与えてくれます
I just told him
私は彼に言ったばかりです
That is to say, Jinwoyin should be placed very, very close
つまり、ジンウォインは非常に近くに配置する必要があります
Then how do I do this thing? I want to control it well.
ではどうすればいいのかというと、うまくコントロールしたいと思っています。
Then this approach becomes an interesting one.
そうなると、このアプローチは興味深いものになります。
If you bring a girl, you will risk your life
女の子を連れてきたら命がけだ
grind it very very flat
とてもとても平らに研ぎます
Otherwise, female grinding flat is not a very soft girl
そうでなければ、平らに磨く女性はあまり柔らかい女の子ではありません
not a very
あまりない
not a very safe thing to do
あまり安全な行為ではありません
Because all the acids you need are explosive.
必要な酸はすべて爆発性があるからです。
Then let's treat it as this Yangji
じゃあこのヤンジとして扱いましょう
Then it moves one by one like this
するとこんな感じで一つ一つ動きます
Then I will use another acid to make this strong
次に、これを強くするために別の酸を使用します
it likes to have a strong cons thickness
強い短所の厚さを好む
it decides by itself
それは自分で決める
You just need to choose the voltage and it decides for itself.
電圧を選択するだけで、自動的に決定されます。
This is completely under its own control
これは完全に独自の制御下にあります
As far as you have only one control, you choose the voltage
コントロールが 1 つしかない限り、電圧を選択します
Then the distance between its movement and movement is determined by it
次に、その動きと動きの間の距離はそれによって決まります
Then the size of its hole is also decided by it
そして、その穴の大きさもそれによって決まります
Then you'll think
それからあなたは考えるでしょう
Then I have this tube because I already have it
それから、このチューブはすでに持っているので持っています
So the wall of this quad is too thin
つまりこのクワッドの壁は薄すぎる
I can just open it up and corrode it
開けて腐食させてもいいよ
into another acid
別の酸に
And then when it's done it's
そしてそれが完了したら、
then i become
それから私はなる
This student from a master’s university did a thing that is the first time in the world to do everyone
修士課程の学生が世界初のことをやった
That is, I can fix the size of each silver particle
つまり、各銀粒子のサイズを固定することができます
Then the distance between to adjust
次に、間の距離を調整します
The point is that what we care about now is the diagonal seam between these two
重要なのは、今私たちが気にしているのは、これら 2 つの間の斜めの継ぎ目であるということです。
The point between the two sets is not close enough
2 つのセット間のポイントが十分に近くありません
We need to be able to accommodate it
それに対応できるようにする必要がある
It does a series like this
こんなシリーズやってます
Then this is an electron that is clearly and imminently waiting
そして、これは明らかに今すぐに待っている電子です
The distance between is to five nanometers
間の距離は最大5ナノメートルです
Let me tell you about five nanometers. I have just shown it to you.
5 ナノメートルについてお話しします。今お見せしました。
The rest of my atom group is three atoms or about five nanometers
私の原子グループの残りの部分は 3 つの原子、つまり約 5 ナノメートルです
Five nanometers means roughly the distance of fifteen atoms
5 ナノメートルは、およそ 15 個の原子の距離を意味します
That is, we almost count the distance atom by atom
つまり、ほぼ原子ごとに距離を数えます。
Then the front of such a nanoparticle with a distance of five nanometers
次に、そのようなナノ粒子の前面の距離は5ナノメートルです
is a world record and is still a world record
これは世界記録であり、今でも世界記録です
That's because of our approach
それは私たちのアプローチによるものです
So it is easy to make very large area
そのため、非常に広い面積を簡単に作ることができます
I have brought my samples here
サンプルをここに持ってきました
Wait a minute and I'll open it up for everyone to see
ちょっと待ってください、みんなに見てもらえるように公開します
see you will feel like saying
ほら、言いたくなるでしょう
no habit
習慣がない
doesn't look like anything
何も見えない
why spend so much time doing
なぜそんなに多くの時間を費やしてしまうのか
Then the particles it wins are placed like this
次に、獲得したパーティクルは次のように配置されます
Put them here one by one
それらを 1 つずつここに置きます
then we'll go and see
それなら行って見ましょう
quickly
素早く
when we do it in a very delicate way
非常に繊細な方法でそれを行うとき
you can see
見ることができます
Win one by one and grow very, very well
ひとつひとつ勝って、とても、とても成長していきます
Then the distance between them is regulated very precisely.
そして、それらの間の距離は非常に正確に調整されます。
Then this one applied for a US patent in 2006
そして、これは2006年に米国特許を申請しました
In 2008, he got the patent in the United States.
2008年に米国で特許を取得した。
Such a wafer technology to make this nanosilver array
このナノ銀アレイを作るためのウェハー技術
get a U.S. patent
米国特許を取得する
Then in 2009 we put this technology
そして 2009 年にこのテクノロジーを導入しました
After one year, it will be transferred to a listed company in Taiwan
1年後に台湾の上場会社に譲渡予定
At that time, when Win was listed, it was called Hongkang.
Winが上場した当時はHongkangと呼ばれていました。
We bought this at Tech
これはテックで購入しました
Just transfer our technology
私たちの技術を移転するだけです
Then I emphasize this thing here
それから、私がここで強調しているのは、
It is not for studying bacteria
細菌を研究するためのものではありません
because i just told you
さっき言ったから
what kind of molecule
どのような分子ですか
just put it on
ただ着てください
i can hear it
聞こえます
So this is a good place to do basic research
したがって、ここは基礎研究を行うのに最適な場所です
Because basic research has a far-reaching impact
基礎研究は広範囲に影響を与えるため
So it can be used to listen to bacteria
細菌の声を聞くために使用できる
A lot of people want you too why don't you
多くの人があなたも望んでいます、なぜあなたもしないのですか
don't do virus
ウイルスはしないでください
In fact, some people also use it as a virus
実際、ウイルスとして利用する人もいます
Then why don't you test the pollutants in the environment
それなら環境中の汚染物質を検査してみませんか
Pollutants in the atmosphere
大気中の汚染物質
These things are molecules anyway
これらはいずれにしても分子です
I can even hear those molecules
その分子の声さえ聞こえる
The availability of this detector
この検出器の可用性
is very very profound
とてもとても奥深いです
So Hongfang Technology is a material analyst
So hongfang Technology は材料アナリストです
They figured this thing out
彼らはこのことを理解した
And now it is actually possible
そして今ではそれが実際に可能になりました
if someone is going to do it
誰かがやろうとしているなら
just do it
早くやれよ
they can bring
彼らはもたらすことができます
Do this kind of service with everyone
こんな奉仕をみんなでやってみよう
but you have to ask first
しかし、最初に尋ねる必要があります
Why spend so much money to listen
なぜそんなにお金をかけて聞くのか
That's probably what a schematic looks like.
概略図としてはおそらくこんな感じでしょう。
That is to say I have a win array
つまり、勝利配列があるということです
What about the winning array?
勝利の配列についてはどうですか？
yes
はい
The size and diameter of each won is about 25 years or so
各ウォンの大きさと直径は約25年程度です
Then the distance between them here
そうすると、ここでの二人の距離は
I want to express the hot zone
ホットゾーンを表現したい
this is the place
ここが場所です
really hot
とても暑い
That's when the laser beam hits
そのときレーザー光線が照射される
It spawns a common gun here
ここで一般的な銃が生成されます
the so-called one
いわゆるもの
The Service surface
サービス面
Plasma, no one can understand me when I say this
プラズマ、これを言っても誰も理解できない
surface plasmons
表面プラズモン
It's the electron over there that is hit by the laser light
レーザー光が当たるのはそこにある電子です
Electrons in active emission are inside this silver
活性放出中の電子はこの銀の中にあります
A bunch of electrons start shaking each other
電子の束が互いに振動し始める
It's like a wave hit it and it vibrated
波が当たって振動したみたいだ
The interaction effect
相互作用効果
so that the electron field in the region between them
そのため、それらの間の領域の電子場は
become very strong
とても強くなる
that looks like the overall effect
それが全体的な効果のように見えます
It's like it's very, very hot in that place
あの場所はとてもとても暑いみたいです
So a molecule that is unfortunate enough to fall into it gets knocked pretty hard
したがって、不運にも分子がそこに落ちてしまうと、かなりの衝撃を受けることになります。
So the sound it emits is very loud, and the signal you measure is very loud
したがって、発する音は非常に大きく、測定する信号も非常に大きくなります。
The entire technology is in such a positive column that the function is in this place
テクノロジー全体が非常にポジティブなコラムにあるため、機能がこの場所にあります
So we use this method to make the surface enhanced light source
そこで、この方法を使用して表面強化光源を作成します
When you make a new technology, it has been 20 or 30 years longer than others
新しい技術を開発する場合、他の技術よりも 20 年、30 年かかります。
Compare it with the traditional method
従来の工法と比べてみる
So what's the traditional way?
では、伝統的な方法とは何でしょうか？
or you take the silver and mess it up and make it rough
さもなければ銀を取り出してめちゃくちゃにして粗末にしてしまう
Etch it with various amounts of acid, or which piece of glass you make
さまざまな量の酸でエッチングするか、どのガラスを作るか
It's got some silver, let's just put some silver on it
銀があるから、それを取ってそれに銀を付けましょう
That's the traditional signal two
それが伝統的なシグナル 2 です
It is mediocre, only here seems to have a little special frequency
平凡だけど、ここだけちょっと特殊な周波数があるみたい
then this is our signal
それならこれが私たちの信号です
very clear this
これは非常に明確です
It is probably ten times better than his traditional ones and more than a hundred times stronger.
おそらく彼の伝統的なものよりも 10 倍優れており、100 倍以上強力です。
That's why many people ask, why do you have such a loud voice?
そのため、多くの人が「なぜそんなに大きな声をするのですか？」と尋ねます。
Then everyone will measure everything
そうしたらみんながすべてを測定します
But there are still many complicated things that I can't talk about today.
しかし、今日は話せない複雑なことがまだたくさんあります。
always a very interesting development
いつもとても興味深い展開です
so that we can really do this so-called
これを実際に実行できるようにするために、いわゆる
When the shooter uses this word, it means to shoot
射手がこの言葉を使うとき、それは撃つことを意味します。
In order to save the surface enhanced spectrum
表面増強スペクトルを保存するために
It's a long story to slow down the spectrum bottom plate
スペクトルの底板の速度を下げるのは長い話です
So I call it the shooter blade technique
だから私はそれをシューターブレードテクニックと呼んでいます
If you want to measure various molecules
さまざまな分子を測定したい場合
It can be measured quite well under different concentrations.
さまざまな濃度下でも非常に良好に測定できます
After doing this, we will start talking
これを行った後、話し合いを始めます
What the hell do we have that thinks so is the amplifier
そう思うものは一体何ですか、それはアンプです
such a sensitive amplifier
あんなに敏感なアンプ
If the method posted next to a certain house is called an amplifier
とある家の隣に貼ってあるメソッドをアンプと呼ぶとしたら
If you eavesdrop on the music in that POP next door
隣のPOPの音楽を盗み聞きしたら
It's too loud for me
私にはうるさすぎる
It's too low for me to hear
低音すぎて聞こえない
So I need to pick certain topics to listen to
だから特定のトピックを選んで聞く必要がある
It just so happened that the person we cooperated with was Professor Lin Qihong from Yangming University.
たまたま協力していただいたのが陽明大学の林啓紅教授でした。
Professor Lin Qihong is currently the director of our Taipei City Health Bureau
林啓紅教授は現在、台北市衛生局の局長です。
Director Lin said most of the time
リン監督はほとんどの場合こう言いました。
You're doing a great job and we're here to do this for you.
あなたは素晴らしい仕事をしており、私たちはあなたのためにこれを行うためにここにいます。
Their interest is probably to study the various manifestations of hygienic creatures
彼らの興味はおそらく衛生的な生き物のさまざまな症状を研究することです
Hygiene, everyone's first reaction is to say
衛生、誰もが最初にこう言います。
Hygienic can you know what he probably passed by so listen to his so-called voice
衛生的、彼がおそらく何を通り過ぎたか知っていますか、だから彼のいわゆる声を聞いてください
Does this know what kind of hygienic creature he is?
これは自分がどんな衛生的な生き物か知っていますか？
Or can you ask about when this hygienic product was poisoned?
それとも、この衛生製品にいつ毒が混入されたかについてお聞きいただけますか?
how did he react
彼はどう反応しましたか
So questions like this are what Professor Lin is more interested in.
したがって、このような質問こそが、リン教授が興味を持っていることなのです。
Then of course we have many others
もちろん他にもたくさんあります
Today I mainly talk about a large part of the cooperation with Professor Lin
今日は主にリン教授との協力の大部分について話します。
Then I will use a graphic to compare with you what you did before.
次に、グラフィックを使用して、以前に行ったことと比較します。
In the past, everyone was an example of producing some nano-silver
過去には、誰もがナノ銀を生産する例でした
then grow some bacteria
それからいくつかのバクテリアを育てます
Then put them together like a muddy one
それから泥のようにそれらを一緒にします
Then measure a spectrum
次にスペクトルを測定します
That's what he said
それが彼が言ったことです
Then he published an article
その後、彼は記事を発表しました
This was published in LNKM Water, a well-known chemical journal
これは有名な化学雑誌である LNKM Water に掲載されました。
and say that's the sound of germs
そしてそれは細菌の音だと言う
tell him it's right
それが正しいと彼に伝えてください
And then many years later when someone else does it
そして何年も経って、他の誰かがそれをしたとき
Both of them are like this
二人ともこんな感じです
So everyone seems to be claiming that it's the sound of this bacterium
だからみんな、これはこのバクテリアの音だと主張しているようだ
Someone said it was the sound of the bacteria
誰かがそれは細菌の音だと言いました
because he is very, very much
なぜなら彼はとてもとても
Why
なぜ
because he's just so hard to repeat
彼は繰り返すのがとても難しいから
Because everyone's formula is different
人それぞれの方程式が違うから
then really in the end
それから本当に最後に
Because my straight man said he came from the voice of bacteria
私の異性愛者が細菌の声から来たと言ったからだ
Then your bacteria live in a different environment
そうすれば、バクテリアは別の環境で生きます
he has different molecules
彼は異なる分子を持っています
Then eat differently
じゃあ違う食べ方をする
So even the same type of bacteria
つまり、同じ種類の細菌であっても、
He may hear different voices
彼には別の声が聞こえるかもしれない
because he emits different molecules
彼は異なる分子を放出するため
So this repeatability is a big problem
したがって、この再現性は大きな問題です
Then it was more like
それからそれはもっと似ていました
It's all fairly stable
どれもかなり安定してるよ
This is a beautiful result
これは美しい結果です
this is a
これは
The spectrum of bacteria in our big factory
私たちの大きな工場内の細菌のスペクトル
It's pretty similar to what we did the first time.
最初にやったこととかなり似ています。
Bacteria like them
細菌はそれらを好みます
Dachang bacteria
大昌菌
you go and see
あなたは行って見ます
His screen also has some
彼の画面にもいくつかあります
Silver particles are placed at the bottom
底には銀粒子が入っています
that same back
同じ背中
Look at his silver particles like this
この銀色の粒子を見てください
Just put them one by one like this
こんな感じで一つずつ並べていくだけです
That's under the exact same index
それはまったく同じインデックスの下にあります
Our silver array looks like this
シルバーの配列は次のようになります
make it bigger
大きくする
Look at each one like a pebble
一つ一つを小石のように見てください
Then every time I think about it myself,
それから、自分で考えるたびに、
my reaction to that germ
その細菌に対する私の反応
that's how it feels
そんな感じです
That is to say, it is like being in the sun
つまり、太陽の下にいるようなものです
Then we find some frogmen
それからフロッグマンを見つけます
and drop it on this pebble beach
そしてこの小石の浜に落として
like the troop on super ice
スーパーアイスの上の軍隊のように
and make them feel
そして彼らに感じさせる
Then do the hard work over there every day
それから毎日あそこでハードワークをしてください
various
様々
make a move over there
あそこに移動してください
And then the sound they give off goes like this
そして彼らが発する音はこんな感じです
The way we did it before is that
以前に行った方法は次のとおりです
The pebbles on the beach are messy
浜辺の小石が汚い
then everywhere
それからどこでも
then we are very very even
それなら私たちはとてもとても平等です
still very very good
まだとてもとても良い
Well, if you want to go down carefully and talk about this
そうですね、慎重に下に降りてこのことについて話したい場合は、
What does the whole image look like
全体像はこんな感じ
that is
あれは
I spread the bacteria on such a
こんなものに菌を撒き散らしてしまう
win array above
上記の勝利配列
That's probably the bacteria
それはおそらく細菌です
Underneath each bacterium is actually
それぞれの細菌の下には実際には
Paved
舗装済み
This servo map doesn't have that much muscle
このサーボ マップにはそれほど力がありません
Under every bacterium
あらゆる細菌の下で
From our scale
弊社の規模からすると
Under each bacterium is paved
各バクテリアの下には舗装されています
An example of one or two thousand winnings
1,000 または 2,000 の賞金の例
under a bacterium
細菌の下で
because of that
そのための
The sawfish between that sawfish is
そのノコギリエイの間のノコギリエイは
around 30nm
約30ナノメートル
It's between the sawfish and the sawfish
ノコギリとノコギリの間です
Sawfish 30
ノコギリギリ 30
Of course the bacteria looks like a microphone
もちろんバクテリアはマイクのように見えます
So it's 30 times 30
つまり 30 掛ける 30 です
There are a lot of examples out there
世の中にはたくさんの例があります
There is a light in there
そこに光がある
This is the shell of a cleanser bacteria
これは洗浄菌の殻です
Each piece is drawn according to size on this picture
それぞれのピースはこの絵のサイズに従って描かれています
This is 25nm, this is 5nm
これは25nm、これは5nm
Bacterial shells probably use these to stand
おそらく細菌の殻はこれを使って立つのでしょう
Probably a sentence of 7 or 80 nanometers
おそらく7または80ナノメートルのセンテンス
That light will penetrate the whole bacteria
その光はバクテリア全体に浸透します
So this blue part is talking about the inside of the bacteria
つまり、この青い部分は細菌の内部について話しているのです
So if you draw according to this rhythm
だからこのリズムで描いたら
The real bacteria is about the size of the roof
本物のバクテリアは屋根ほどの大きさです
live so big
とても大きく生きる
It's such a big thing that the color light shoots in
色の光が射し込むのはとても大きなことだ
then the distance
それから距離
Bacteria no matter what it emits
細菌は何を放出しても
Or the signal on the wall that is about 10 nanometers nearby
または近くの壁にある約10ナノメートルの信号
the sound of those molecules
その分子の音
we can all hear
私たち全員が聞くことができます
So I just gave you
だから私はあなたにあげただけです
Let me show you those spectra
私がお見せするスペクトル
It's actually a big chorus
実は大合唱なんです
It's a lot of molecules together
たくさんの分子が集まったものです
the overall effect is taking place
全体的な効果が起きている
Not just one bacterium
細菌は1つだけではありません
is a bacterium
細菌です
exudes a lot
たくさん滲み出る
many molecules those molecules have in common
それらの分子に共通する多くの分子
A shimmer of vibration
振動のきらめき
Bacteria can explain to you a little bit here
ここで細菌について少し説明できます
Basically, there are two classes
基本的には2つのクラスがあります
It is the Yangshi bacteria in Ge'an City and the Yinshi bacteria in Ge'an City
吉安市の陽士菌と吉安市の陰士菌です。
The whole category is roughly like this
全体のカテゴリーは大体こんな感じです
Then they wait a minute and I will tell everyone to see him
それから彼らは少し待ってください、そして私は皆に彼に会うように言います
Anshi Yangshi Bacteria
隔安市陽市菌
He has a typical scrambling voice
彼は典型的なスクランブルな声を持っています
When there are molecules under these
この下に分子があると
He has a very, very loud voice
彼はとてもとても大きな声を持っています
is 733
733です
Guo Shu
郭叔
Wait a minute and I'll explain this to you 733
ちょっと待ってください。説明します 733
Just what you want to say about 733 times
言いたいことだけ733回
But this time we have to multiply by
しかし今回は次の値を乗算する必要があります
Three times ten to the tenth power like this
このように 3 倍の 10 の 10 乗
Another kind of example
別の種類の例
Anshi Yinshi Bacteria
安士陰士菌
Everyone is most familiar with Escherichia coli
誰もが最もよく知っている大腸菌
That's what everyone often hears about bacteria in Yangshi, Anshi.
それは、安市楊石の細菌について誰もがよく聞くことです。
Botrytis aureus
黄色ブドウ球菌
This is one of these two types of bacteria
これはこれら 2 種類の細菌のうちの 1 つです
Then there is this category
続いてはこのカテゴリーです
Molecular infection
分子感染
Molecular infectious bacteria look like tigers
分子状の感染性細菌はトラに似ている
It has co-existed with us humans for thousands of years
何千年もの間私たち人間と共存してきました
Mycobacterium fidgetii
マイコバクテリウム・フィゲティ
Mycobacteria
マイコバクテリア
Mycobacterium Naficella is a very, very tough home
マイコバクテリウム・ナフィセラは非常にタフな住処です
it can hide inside your body
体の中に隠れることもある
Then never get sick
それなら絶対に病気にならないでください
wait until you're older
大人になるまで待ってください
it just started to trouble you
それはあなたを悩ませ始めたばかりです
Another branch of mycobacterium is let us
マイコバクテリウムの別の系統を見てみましょう
Everyone has a lot of text settings
誰もがたくさんのテキスト設定を持っています
that's where we are
そこが私たちのいる場所です
we are over there
私たちはそこにいる
Many texts are set to be leprosy
多くのテキストがハンセン病であると設定されている
Leprosy is also a type of mycobacterium
ハンセン病も抗酸菌の一種です
those two
あの二人
What about this type of infection?
この種の感染症はどうなるのでしょうか？
Mycobacterium
マイコバクテリウム
Its spectrum is like everything else
そのスペクトルは他のものと同じです
big difference
大きな違い
just the same
全く同じで
let's wait
待とう
I will probably let everyone listen to this voice
この声をきっとみんなに聴かせてあげる
how did it play
どうやって遊んだの？
Then I'm going to
それから私は行きます
heard about it
それについて聞いた
not really us
実は私たちではありません
I just heard that go to the room
部屋に行くと聞いたところです
not really our biggest concern
実は私たちの最大の懸念ではありません
What we are actually more concerned with is that
私たちが実際にもっと懸念しているのは、
How did Xixun react when we poisoned him?
私たちが彼に毒を盛ったとき、Xixunはどう反応しましたか?
because why
なぜならなぜ
Because if you're going to talk to someone who does medicine
なぜなら、薬をやっている人と話すつもりなら
For example, when we talked with the doctor of National Taiwan University
たとえば、国立台湾大学の博士と話をしたときのことです。
They said you should not tell me which strain it is so detailed
どの菌株がそんなに詳しいのか教えてはいけないと言われました
Because I only have three medicines
薬が3つしかないので
One is isolated positive bacteria
一つは分離された陽性菌
One is specialized in medical isolation type negative bacteria
1つは医療分離型陰性菌に特化したもの
Then the other one is the plum fungus
それからもう一つは梅菌です
Just tell me these three
この3つを教えてください
Anyway, I only have these three options for medication.
とにかく、薬の選択肢はこの3つだけです。
you won't tell me too much about medicine
あなたは私に薬についてあまり教えてくれません
Just tell me these three
この3つだけ教えてください
Then I started taking drugs
それから薬を飲み始めた
if you don't tell me
あなたが教えてくれなければ
Then I will download all three
次に、3 つすべてをダウンロードします
Then when the time comes, let’s talk about the abuse of antibiotics anyway.
そして、その時が来たら、とにかく抗生物質の乱用について話しましょう。
It's because the upper management told me not to use it.
上層部から「使うな」と言われたからです。
But from the patient's point of view
しかし患者さんの立場からすると
our family is dying
私たちの家族は死につつあります
Of course you just drop all the atomic bombs and everything
もちろん、原爆などすべてを投下するだけです
And then it looks like there's something going on
そして、死ぬほど何かがあるようだ
When you are about to die, there will be one less and one less
あなたが死にそうになると、一人ずつ減っていきます。
see if he survives
彼が生き残るかどうか見てみる
you usually look like this
あなたは普段こんな感じです
So antibiotics say no to abuse
したがって、抗生物質は乱用にノーを言います
It's actually very difficult
実はとても難しいんです
that sentence i said
私が言ったその文
I didn't say it, but they took it and tied it all down
私は言いませんでしたが、彼らはそれを受け取り、すべてを縛り付けました
This is what Mr. Ke Wenzhe told me
柯文哲氏が私にこう言った。
Because Mr. Ke Wenzhe is the boss of a Korean doctor in our cooperative team
柯文哲氏は私たちの協力チームの韓国人医師の上司だから
As far as the medicines probably cost money, there are probably four types of medicines
薬に関して言えば、おそらく4種類の薬があります。
The first way to think of attacking others is probably
他人を攻撃することについて最初に思いつくのは、おそらく次のようなものでしょう。
The hardest, and easiest-to-shake method
最も難しくて振りやすい方法
Just when the family is splitting
ちょうど家族が離散しつつあるとき
to attack, that is to say
攻撃する、つまり
Being careful doesn't mean growing up, his shell always grows up
注意することが成長を意味するわけではない、彼の殻は常に成長する
So I figured out a way to stop him from growing out of the shell
そこで私は彼が殻から出て成長するのを止める方法を考え出しました
Or break his shell, because he wants to grow
あるいは殻を破る、成長したいから
That doesn't end up growing, there's always a weakness
それは結局成長しない、常に弱さがある
If you cut him off at that time, he will list the information
その時に彼を切ると、彼は情報をリストアップします
It's a kind of shell that's attacking his cells
それは彼の細胞を攻撃する一種の貝殻です
The other is the synthesis of proteins that go in and attack his cells
もう1つは、細胞に入り込んで攻撃するタンパク質の合成です。
Don't let his protein cells
彼にその細胞をタンパク質化させないでください
probably won't last
おそらく続かないでしょう
The third way is to directly turn the entire outer shell of the cell into a
3 番目の方法は、細胞の外殻全体を直接に変えることです。
This is also the fourth
こちらも4つ目です
The fourth is the process of how to make the DNA in it
4つ目はその中にDNAを作るプロセスです
let's keep fucking it
クソ続けましょう
then fix it
それからそれを修正してください
it won't survive or grow
それは生き残ることも成長することもありません
A germ can't kill you
細菌はあなたを殺すことはできません
Would you be a million short
100万足りないですか？
A bacterium will not
細菌はそうはなりません
you are afraid of it
あなたはそれを恐れています
You have no reason to be afraid of cockroaches
ゴキブリを恐れる理由はありません
But you're right to be afraid of germs
でも細菌を恐れるのは正しい
Because if the bacteria arrive
菌が入ってきたら
copy two two two two every half hour
30分ごとに2つ、2つ、2つをコピーします
At the time of the twenty-fourth square, it will soon take up the reputation of this body
24歳、この体はすぐにその評判を引き継ぐだろう
Therefore, it is only needed when the calamity is small
したがって、災害が小さい場合にのみ必要です。
Ant, you don't need to be too nervous
アリ、あまり緊張する必要はありません
But when you start to lose sight you just get nervous
でも、目が見えなくなり始めると、不安になるだけです
By the time I can't see it, it's already thinner than your hair
見えなくなったらもう髪の毛よりも細い
Your hair is about 100 micrometer
髪の毛の長さは約100マイクロメートル
The bacteria I'm talking about is your hair and cut it into a hundred pieces
つまり、私が話しているバクテリアはあなたの髪の毛であり、それを100本の部分に切ります
into a million
百万に
one hundred
百
One Hundred Feet Zun
百フィートのズン
We're probably just starting to say yes, then we'll read on.
おそらく私たちは「はい」と言い始めたばかりです。それから読み進めましょう。
We read it from bacteria
細菌からそれを読み取る
You can see the result of the next reading, that is to say
次回の読み取り結果がわかります。
I have written about the birth and death of bacteria after we read it
細菌の誕生と死について読んでから書きました。
So it was a joy to start him reading Bacteria
だから彼に細菌の本を読み始めたのはとても嬉しかったです
Like a whale in the bottom of the sea singing his own favorite song
海の底で自分の好きな歌を歌うクジラのように
Just the same spectrum doesn't change
同じスペクトルだけは変わらない
just keep walking
ただ歩き続けてください
At 50 minutes, he suddenly knew and said wow
50分後、彼は突然気づいて「すごい」と言いました。
He's already been attacked.
彼はすでに攻撃を受けています。
So his entire spectrum has completely changed.
つまり、彼のスペクトル全体が完全に変わりました。
then to the last
それから最後まで
After waiting for a while, he answered the spectrum again
しばらく待ってから、彼は再びスペクトルに応答しました
I won't talk about that detail today
今日はその詳細については話しません
In fact, we've had a lot of work on this spectrum lately.
実際、私たちは最近、このスペクトルに関して多くの作業を行ってきました。
What exactly does that mean
それは正確にどういう意味ですか
we have a deeper understanding
私たちはより深い理解を持っています
But today we don't like him
でも今日、私たちは彼のことを好きではありません
Remember these numbers the point is to say
これらの数字を覚えておいてください。重要なのは、
about a pinhead
ピンヘッドについて
Bacteria already feel his pain
細菌はすでに痛みを感じている
Then start teaching
それから教え始めてください
Then we'll give all kinds of medicine
それからあらゆる種類の薬を出します
Teacher Lin Xuhong and his laboratory
林徐紅先生と研究室
There are various
いろいろあります
All kinds of poisonous hands, they all have a way to do this
あらゆる種類の毒手、彼らは皆これを行う方法を持っています
So what they do is
そこで彼らがやっているのは、
If you're off the drug, you'll be fine listening to him all the time.
薬をやめたら、いつも彼の話を聞いていても大丈夫だよ
There are such drugs as
などの薬があります
Drugs of this class that grow on the epidermis of the main segment bacteria
主要部分の細菌の表皮で増殖するこのクラスの薬剤
That's 55 minutes 45 minutes
それは55分45分です
about an hour or so
約1時間くらい
They bacteria start to give birth
彼らの細菌は出産を始めます
His so-called procreation means
彼のいわゆる生殖手段は、
There is a huge change in Optics Valley
オプティクスバレーに大きな変化が起こる
It's that voice that sounds sudden
突然聞こえるその声
You thought you were listening to the cello
チェロを聴いていると思ったでしょう
suddenly became sona
突然ソナになった
or something
か何か
what it sounds like happened
何が起こったように聞こえるか
so
それで
The other category is to
もう一つのカテゴリーは、
During protein synthesis in the main segment bacteria
細菌のメインセグメントにおけるタンパク質合成中
sounds reasonable
合理的に聞こえる
quite reasonable
かなり合理的
idiom like flame
炎のようなイディオム
After waiting for half a day
半日待った後
12 hours later
12時間後
Bacteria finally suffocated
細菌はついに窒息した
hold for half an hour
30分間保持する
After half a day, I finally couldn't take it anymore
半日経って、ついに我慢できなくなった
started giving birth
出産を始めた
this is very interesting
これはとても興味深いです
see this time
今回を見てください
Actually for this matter
実はこの件に関しては
Especially an instant detection response of wanting to heal or something
特に癒したいとか何かを瞬時に察知する反応
may be useful
役に立つかもしれない
they are
彼らはこれらのことについてです
Such a method fast one
このような方法は速いものです
detection
検出
Then directly observe in the monitor
そしてモニターで直接観察
Such an instant response technology
このような即時応答技術
they are interested
彼らは興味があります
Then we sat there and wanted to say
それから私たちはそこに座って言いたかったのです
what are we going to do next
次は何をしましょうか
Already talked to him and it sounds like it might work.
すでに彼と話し合っており、うまくいきそうな気がします。
The next step, of course, is to be the station master.
次のステップはもちろん駅長です。
Just say yes, or you can catch a few bacteria to really catch them all.
「はい」と答えるか、いくつかの細菌を捕まえるだけで、すべての細菌を確実に捕まえることができます。
what bacteria to catch
どのような細菌を捕まえるのか
The first one is that of course we will go to school to catch
1つ目は、もちろん学校に行ってキャッチすることです
why
なぜ
Our real science should not have bacteria in it
私たちの本当の科学には細菌が存在すべきではありません
If there are bacteria, it is called
細菌がいる場合、それは呼び出されます
Bacteriology certificate or university certificate
細菌学の証明書または大学の証明書
when you catch bacteria
細菌を捕まえると
it will be painful
苦しいだろう
That
それか
These
これらは
It's about time. I can, maybe, tell a few jokes.
そろそろ時間ですので、いくつかジョークを言ってもいいかもしれません。
that is
あれは
That's because when I started doing it, I started going around
やり始めたらぐるぐるし始めたから。
ask and report
聞いて報告する
We're going to send the machine to National Taiwan University Hospital
この機械を国立台湾大学病院に送ります
That's when I started to know
そのとき私は知り始めました
What is played in the Japanese contact drama is called the white drama tower
日本の接触ドラマにおける白いドラマタワーとは何ですか？
in this way
この上
That's the one
それだ
No matter how you say it, you have to go over there and bet on a small place.
なんと言っても、あそこに行って小さいところに賭けないといけないんです。
The machine will be given to you and then what?
機械があなたに与えられ、その後はどうなるでしょうか？
Send an assistant to help you with the experiment
実験を手伝ってくれるアシスタントを派遣する
you don't spend a dime
あなたは一銭も使わない
you just let us come here with you
あなたは私たちをここに一緒に来させてくれただけです
Then I will report the result to you after finishing
それでは終了後に結果をご報告させていただきます
Why don't you go in?
入ってみませんか？
Later, I had no choice but to find Dean Yang at that time.
その後、当時のディーン・ヤンを見つけるしかありませんでした。
Yang half time
ヤンハーフタイム
Yang Banshi worked very hard to help us explain
楊蛮師は私たちの説明を一生懸命手伝ってくれました
Then one day I met Principal Li at that time
そんなある日、当時のリー校長に会いました。
Principal Li Sicheng
李四成李校長
Principal Li told me about this
李校長が私にこのことを話しました。
Yang Banshi
ヤン・バンシ
Yang Banshima is not enough to legislate
楊伴島は立法するには足りない
I should be more capable
もっと能力があればいいのに
National Taiwan University this
国立台湾大学はこちら
only two are fourteen
14歳は二人だけ
one is medicine
一つは薬です
hospital director
病院長
The other is the principal
もう一人は校長です
so there should be a way
だから方法があるはずだ
After he finished speaking, there was an interval of five minutes
彼が話し終えた後、5分間の休憩があった
he wants to say
彼は言い​​たいのです
I think I probably can't do this
多分これは出来ないと思う
What do you call a white lens?
白いレンズを何と呼びますか？
Then Mr. Yang is very busy
それからヤンさんはとても忙しいです
Then go talk to the dean of the medical school
それから医学部長に話してください
Talk to the director of the hospital
病院の院長に相談する
We are finally in the department in the important town
いよいよ重要な町の部署に到着です
just find a place
ただ場所を見つけてください
a very small corner
とても小さな隅
Then you can help others to do experiments there
そうすれば、他の人がそこで実験を行うのを手伝うことができます
It's totally free
完全に無料です
to help people do experiments
人々が実験をするのを助けるために
It's so hard to do this thing
これをやるのはとても難しいです
Because it's from the Congress
議会からの発言だから
Nanostate project
ナノステートプロジェクト
So they want us to have some industrial applications
それで彼らは私たちにいくつかの産業応用を望んでいます
So I personally spent a lot of effort
なので個人的にはかなりの労力を費やしました
then do this
それからこれをしてください
Of course the first thing is fine
もちろん最初は大丈夫です
Then you're going to catch bacteria
そうすると細菌がついてしまうよ
like say
言うように
Yang's bacteria are
ヤン菌は、
That is the feeding machine
それが給餌機です
If you really want to catch bacteria
本気で菌を捕まえたいなら
Then go grab and release the flasher
次にフラッシャーを掴んで放します
That's when we caught the machine first
その時、私たちは最初にマシンを捕まえた
otherwise how did you come
そうでなければどうやって来たの
Is it necessary to find a way to catch it?
それを捕まえる方法を見つける必要がありますか？
Then we later had a professor
その後、教授が来ました
this is the one
これがそれです
He was my blogging researcher at the time
彼は当時私のブログの研究者でした
Professor Liu Dinghong
劉鼎紅教授
Now at the Department of Materials Science at National Taiwan University
現在、国立台湾大学材料科学部に在籍
He proposed a method at that time
彼はその時ある方法を提案した
Just count all these things
これらすべてを数えてみてください
Du on the array surface we win
アレイ表面の Du で我々が勝ちます
Wangu Homestay itself is a medicine
ワング ホームステイ自体が薬です
It's actually a tool next to the connection of the protein
実はタンパク質の接続の隣にあるツールなんです
Wangu Homestay is a medicine
ワング ホームステイは薬です
this thing is interesting
これは面白いですね
Why does medicine help you catch bacteria
なぜ薬が細菌を捕まえるのに役立つのか
This thing is intuitive
このことは直感的です
It's funny looking back now
今振り返ると面白いですね
But it was just a sense of fact
でもそれは単なる事実感だった
It turned out really well.
本当にうまくいきました。
like here is to say
ここで言うように
It's just a little lower on top of my floor
床の上の少し低いところにあります
The place of Wangu B&B is just a little low
万古民宿の場所は少し低いところにあります
Then this little low size
それからこの少し低いサイズ
This one is only about ten or fifteen microns.
これはわずか10ミクロンか15ミクロン程度です。
a small area
小さなエリア
Where there is a low place, the bacteria will be in the water
低いところがあると水中にバクテリアがいる
Then just shake it and wait
あとは振って待つだけです
wait ten or twenty minutes later
10分か20分後に待ってください
found that bacteria only stick to this
バクテリアはここにのみ付着することがわかりました
I caught the bacteria
菌を捕まえてしまった
like say put some in there and run countdown
そこに何かを入れてカウントダウンを実行するように
Or in fact, it is more like the previous Margin Camp
言い換えれば、実際には以前のマージンキャンプに似ています。
that warehouse paper
あの倉庫の紙
Just put a meal here
ここに食事を置くだけ
Then
それから
When I come back from get off work, I will watch it for three and a half years
仕事から帰ったら3年半見るよ
Everyone will feel that this
これは誰もが感じるだろう
Think of medicine as a catch thing
薬を捕まえるものとして考える
Then it can be used to measure the tiger
そうすればトラの測定に使用できます
This is a semi-accidental discovery
これは半ば偶然の発見でした
This result quickly attracted the attention of many people.
この結果はすぐに多くの人々の注目を集めました。
actually looking back
実際に振り返ってみると
I just said that when building this thing
これを作るときに言いました
Actually, I have a logic in my heart
実は心の中には理屈があるんだ
The logic is this is to say
論理的にはこう言えます
why the medicine works
なぜ薬が効くのか
In fact, we have used the medicine for a long time with great motivation.
実際、私たちはこの薬を長い間、大きなモチベーションを持って使用してきました。
don't even know why it works
なぜそれが機能するのかさえわかりません
In fact, we are still looking for the philosophy of medicine
実は私たちは今も医学哲学を模索中です
There is actually no difference between the license plate of the mayor of Shenlong
神龍市長のナンバープレートには実際には違いはありません
We are not much stronger than Shenlong City
私たちは神龍城よりもそれほど強くありません
We just agreed on what kind of molecule I would synthesize.
私たちはどのような分子を合成するかについて合意しただけです。
Then I'll try it out
じゃあ試してみるよ
If it is effective or not, it will continue to moisten every day if it is effective or not
効果があってもなくても、毎日潤い続けます。
that's the whole thing
それがすべてです
like vancomyle knows it works
ヴァンコマイルはそれがうまくいくことを知っているかのように
it's been a long time
おひさしぶりですね
But how to kill the bacteria
しかし、どうやって細菌を殺すのか
this matter to this day
この件は今日に至るまで
It is not very clear that
それはあまり明確ではありません
because that mechanism is a hard problem
そのメカニズムは難しい問題だから
But effective energy is a test method that can be used to do
しかし、有効エネルギーは、次の目的で使用できるテスト方法です。
Wangu plum tree has been known for thirty or forty years
王古梅の木は 30 ～ 40 年前から知られています。
I was thinking about my opinion on the matter
このことについて考えていました
It's four steps
4ステップです
If the everlasting plum tree enters your studies
永遠の梅の木があなたの書斎に入ったら
cells everywhere
どこにでもある細胞
Or if the classmates stick together
あるいはクラスメイトがくっついたら
Then you must be carrying a lot of weight
そうすると、かなりの重量を背負っているはずです
Then you are already dead, right?
じゃあもう死んでるよね？
then he must have a way
それなら彼には方法があるはずだ
It's like the key and lock method
キーアンドロック方式のようなものです
he goes to find something he likes sticky
彼は好きなものを探しに行きます
Then if he is effective against bacteria
それで細菌に対して効果があるなら
He should be with him at least like to be close together
彼は少なくとも近くにいるように彼と一緒にいるべきです
Under such a concept
そんなコンセプトのもとに
we just do some searching
ちょっと検索するだけです
The everlasting plum tree happens to be here half a year at this corner
永遠の梅の木はたまたま半年だけこの街角にある
But recently we've made some very subtle discoveries
しかし最近、私たちは非常に微妙な発見をしました
How on earth did the plum tree accumulate and develop this bacteria sticking in it?
いったいどのようにして梅の木に細菌が蓄積し、付着して発生したのでしょうか？
Actually there is a very interesting story
実はとても興味深い話があるのです
Then I hope after a year
それから1年後を願っています
I can tell you a better story
もっと良い話をできるよ
As a result, the result of the measurement is like this, that is, when you took ten thousand shares of plum trees and pasted them
その結果、梅の木を1万株とって貼り付けた場合の測定結果はこうなりました
Where the amount of bacteria is not added to the plum tree, the red snowball prefers to stick to it
梅の木にバクテリアが十分に添加されていない場合、赤い雪玉は梅の木に付着することを好みます。
The place where the plum tree is added is that the bacteria prefer to stick to it
梅の木を入れる場所は細菌が好んで付着するためです。
Just when you're elected, it makes some sense to our intuition
あなたが選出されている限り、それは私たちの直感ではある程度理にかなっています
If Wangu Meishu likes to stick to your red snowball when it goes in, then something is probably wrong with you
ワング・メイシュがあなたの赤い雪玉が入ってくるときにくっつくのを好むなら、おそらくあなたに何か問題があるでしょう。
If you take one injection, you will die first, and the bacteria will not be there, because it can't find the bacteria
1回注射すると、まずあなたが死に、細菌は存在しません。細菌を見つけることができないからです。
Then go to your student's side and beat around, and then let the red snowball go on it
それから生徒の側に行って殴り、その上に赤い雪玉を乗せます。
so this whole afternoon looks like fun
だから今日の午後はずっと楽しそうだ
Then it turns out that the relationship between time, I think I must find some time
そうすると、時間の関係が判明したので、時間を見つけなければいけないと思います
Then broadcast the sound of bacteria for you to click off, otherwise there must be members
次にバクテリアの音をブロードキャストしてクリックしてください。そうでない場合はメンバーがいるはずです
As a result, of course we spent a lot, the team is very big
その結果、もちろん多額の費用を費やしましたが、チームは非常に大きくなりました
Spend a lot of time researching and saying, if we really want to be useful
本当に役に立ちたいなら、リサーチと発言に多くの時間を費やす
How to improve the settings of the instrument
楽器の設定を改善する方法
What our lab is doing is probably, all the labs use such equipment
私たちの研究室がやっているのは、おそらくこのような装置を使っている研究室です。
that is
あれは
The equipment used in the lab is phantom active
研究室で使用されている機器はファントムアクティブです
equipment is expensive
設備が高価である
It was the Zhuangren circle who gave it to me
くれたのは荘仁サークルです
i will give my experience
私の経験を教えます
brought it and bought the machine
それを持ってきて機械を買った
To the team I work with at Yangming University
陽明大学で一緒に働いているチームへ
The way I work with him is to say who and which team member needs
私が彼と協力する方法は、チームメンバーの誰が必要かを言うことです。
give him the machine
彼に機械をあげてください
Then write a letter to laugh with them
それなら一緒に笑い合うために手紙を書きましょう
I told him about the machine I'm giving to your co-op team
私は彼にあなたの協力チームに与える機械について話しました
then can you give him a space
それなら彼にスペースを与えてもらえませんか
After asking for half a day
半日お願いしてから
finally reached
ついに到達した
Do you have a hard time giving you a small room
狭い部屋を与えるのは大変ですか
you send that phantom machine
あなたはそのファントムマシンを送ります
Then we sent a
それから私たちは
until now put
今まで入れた
So it's really good to work with me
だから私と一緒に仕事ができて本当に良かったです
that machine
あの機械
very very strict
とてもとても厳しい
Many things are very elf
多くのものは非常にエルフです
I just saw that most of the materials are made from such machines
ほとんどの材料がそのような機械で作られているのを見ました
but you have to put
しかし、あなたは置かなければなりません
You can't put a phantom machine in the hospital
病院にファントムマシンを置くことはできない
that phantom machine is too big
そのファントムマシンは大きすぎる
That big hospital every time
いつもあの大きな病院
There's only one piece of each and it's that big
それぞれ1個ずつしかないのに、こんなに大きいのです
Put hundreds of cameras in
何百台ものカメラを設置
So start my co-op partner
それで、協力パートナーを始めましょう
the long-term cooperation
長期的なパートナー
It is Wang Jingqiao from the Tie Center of National Taiwan University driving the car
車を運転するのは国立台湾大学タイセンターの王京橋さんです
At once
すぐに
designed to make the whole thing very, very small
全体を非常に小さくするように設計されています
a microscope, then a spectrum
顕微鏡、そしてスペクトル
or something, take it all
または何か、すべてを受け取ってください
It's a bit table-oriented
少しテーブル指向です
Then we also put a machine in the Central Administration Bureau of Taiwan
それから台湾の中央管理局にも機械を置きました
because of careful research
綿密な調査のおかげで
May be to P2 Level
P2レベルになる可能性があります
Mainly what we do over there is mycobacteria
あそこで私たちがやっているのは主にマイコバクテリアです
that machine
あの機械
When students go in, you all operate N95
学生が入ってくると、皆さんはN95を操作します
I go in every day and do experiments like that
私は毎日行ってそのような実験をしています
that was a very, very hard experiment
それはとてもとても難しい実験でした
that requires very little space
必要なスペースが非常に少ない
and then inside the life safety cabinet
それから生命安全キャビネットに
So there are actually a lot of sad stories in it.
なので、実際には悲しい話もたくさんあります。
I don't talk about time today.
今日は時間の話はしません。
that if
もし
If you stand down, just say yes, if you may want to be in
降りるなら、参加したいなら「はい」と言ってください
really smaller space
本当に小さなスペース
then you are the one
それならあなたがその人です
The machine doesn't need to be so good, then you can make something like a desktop
マシンはそれほど優れている必要はなく、デスクトップのようなものを作ることができます
So put the whole design to say
デザイン全体を一言で言えば、
My wafer is the one that can put the wafer
私のウエハースはウエハースを入れることができるものです
That chip is for biologists to get used to
あのチップは生物学者が慣れるためのものだ
So our chip is basically made in
したがって、私たちのチップは基本的に次のように作られています。
Just make it what everyone is used to
誰もが慣れているものにしてください
It's the Bone Noodle House
ボーンヌードルハウスです
This is it
これだよ
this product
この製品
look
見て
It's like a pixel
ピクセルのようなものです
if you speak directly
直接話せば
this is above
これは上です
yours
あなたのもの
You don't take it, you keep hitting it
あなたはそれを受け取らず、それを打ち続けます
a little bit of what you see above
上に表示されているものを少しだけ
so just a little click
それで少しクリックしてください
Simple and feels like the upper half
シンプルで上半身っぽい感じ
is your button
あなたのボタンです
that's it
それでおしまい
relatively stable
比較的安定
That's dense enough
それは十分な密度です
then one by one
それから一つ一つ
what does your fingerprint sound like
あなたの指紋はどんな音ですか
right
右
Then it becomes very
そうなるととてもなります
for the entire process
プロセス全体に対して
or give us the possibility to generate very quickly
または、非常に迅速に生成する可能性を提供してください
many such detectors
多くのそのような検出器
You think of it as an amplifier
アンプとして考えると
and then you stick it on something
それから何かに貼り付けます
you have the opportunity to hear the molecular voice
分子の声を聞く機会があります
Do you want to listen to basic training?
基礎トレーニングを聞いてみませんか？
Because we found a partner who happened to be doing basic training
たまたま基礎訓練をしているパートナーを見つけたので
If anyone here would like to hear other
ここで他のことを聞きたい人がいれば、
Or like to eavesdrop on what other people are saying
または、他の人が言っていることを盗み聞きするのが好きです
don't care
気にしないでください
Then of course I still have the answer to my dream
もちろん夢の答えはまだある
Because I just said that those are small ones.
なぜなら、それらは小さいものだと今言ったからです。
Jihun is 1 million smaller than us
ジフンは私たちより100万小さい
1 million times
100万回
why so big
なぜそんなに大きいのか
It's a big deal for Kihun
キフンにとっては大事なことだ
big to the first step
最初の一歩への大きな
unbelievable is
信じられないです
People are weak
人は弱いものです
less popular
人気が低い
to do
すること
if the real future
本当の未来なら
if to do
やるなら
make it such a big one
それをとても大きなものにしてください
hand in hand
手をつないで
So this is pretending to be a photo
つまりこれは写真のふりをしているのです
Then we follow this photo
それからこの写真をたどっていきます
and then like this
そしてこのように
just not the same
ただ同じではない
Separated things should then still
分離したものは静止しているはずです
Just put it on the back of this photo
この写真の裏側に貼ってください
is twitter
ツイッターです
That's my bacteria from last night
それは昨夜の私のバクテリアです
what song did you sing to me like this
こんな風に私に歌ってくれたのは何の曲ですか？
that's a good idea too
それも良いアイデアですね
so
それで
The technology of miniaturization is not a
小型化の技術は単なる技術ではありません。
real problem
本当の問題
The problem is in the self-preparation of the sample
問題はサンプルの自己調製にあります
Get the samples and prepare yourself
サンプルを入手して準備してください
I managed to get into National Taiwan University Hospital this year
今年なんとか国立台湾大学病院に入院することができました
What you do in pain every day
あなたが毎日痛みを抱えてやっていること
those things are not my specialty
それらのことは私の専門ではありません
It turns out that those are the expertise of life scientists
それらは生命科学者の専門知識であることが判明
How many molecules are there in that
その中には分子が何個あるのか
There are many, many molecules in a drop of blood
一滴の血液の中には非常に多くの分子が含まれています
those molecules in the end
それらの分子は最終的には
meaning that he may be in
彼がいるかもしれないという意味
At least find a child, right?
少なくとも子供を見つけてくださいね？
Then you'd be making a fuss
そしたら大騒ぎするだろうね
then how on earth do you listen to him
じゃあ一体どうやって彼の言うことを聞くの？
Why did you stop him from happening first?
なぜ最初に彼の事件を阻止したのですか？
Then hand it over and get rid of it first
それからそれを渡して、最初にそれを処分してください
why this whole bunch of things
なぜこんなにたくさんのことがあるのか
It was when you were experimenting
実験していた時のことだ
very simple
とてもシンプルな
I'm so happy when I'm writing a thesis
論文を書いているときはとても楽しいです
Then when the reporter was waiting for the meeting
それから記者が会議を待っているとき
nor
または
Very happy, not very happy, but my collaborators are very happy
とても幸せ、あまり幸せではありませんが、私の協力者たちはとても幸せです
There are three minutes left, let's listen to the sound
残り3分です、音を聞いてみましょう
If this speaker does not broadcast sound, please donate a little more money when you go out, and you will finally be like this
このスピーカーで音が出ない場合は、出かけるときにもう少しお金を寄付してください。そうすれば、最終的にはこのようになります
This is Mr. Dachangan, what you have measured is such a light map
こちらはダチャンガンさん、あなたが計測したのはこんなライトマップです
I will play this main one, according to this size, the 10 most important and louder sounds, I will start playing according to the loudest sound
このメインの音をこのサイズに従って演奏します。最も重要で大きな音 10 個を演奏します。最も大きな音に従って演奏を開始します。
The background sound gets rid of it first, that's the kind of background
背景音を先に消してしまう、そんな背景です
The ten sound waves I picked, I have a lot of waves, I can also make all ten sounds cooperate
私が選んだ10個の音波、たくさんの波がある、10個すべての音を連携させることもできる
At the beginning, did anyone recognize the 700-odd sound?
最初、700数音の音に気づいた人はいるでしょうか？
Can anyone tell me that it is really a positive frequency of 720 or so
それが実際には720程度の正の周波数であることを誰か教えてください。
Then this is mycobacteria, so let's remove the background
それでは、これはマイコバクテリアなので、背景を削除しましょう
Louder, louder, louder, louder
音量比較高,音量比較高,音量比較高,音量比較高
The wave size of its sound is related to its volume, the higher the volume, the more and longer the volume of my wave
音の波のサイズは音量に関係しており、音量が大きいほど、私の波の音量は大きくなり、長くなります。
Then this is very interesting, this Pip is in seven hundred and thirty-three
それから、これは非常に興味深いです、このピップは 733 にあります
This is Staphylococcus aureus
これは黄色ブドウ球菌です
All Glanz Yang Zhijun has this one strong signal
すべての Glanz Yang Zhijun にはこの 1 つの強力なシグナルがあります
I've been talking to him for five years
私は彼と5年間話し続けています
Why must follow his 8 points
なぜ彼の 8 つのポイントに従わなければならないのか
In fact, there are infinitely many low-pitched
実際、低音は無数にあります。
which sound is dishonest
どの音が不誠実なのか
good
良い
next
次
I can't do this look anymore
もうこの表情はできない
good
良い
just use this air
この空気を使ってください
Well, at the end of the speech, thanks to the people who actually did the work
さて、スピーチの最後に、本当に物事を行っている人々に感謝したいと思います。
people who actually do things
実際に物事を行う人
People who are squinting and rolling their eyes are usually right.
目を細めて目を丸くしている人は、たいてい正しいです。
So I'm just thinking about it
だから私はちょうどそれについて考えています
It was the three of us who went there together
私たち３人でそこに行きました
This phenomenon of speech in life
生活の中での発話というこの現象
The life speech that awards us the Lord
私たちに主を授ける人生のスピーチ
please stand
お立ちください
He is Wang Jianchang
彼は王建昌です
adults are there
大人がそこにいる
he is also avoided
彼も避けられている
He is the current member director
彼は現在のメンバーディレクターです
so you are in our building
それであなたは私たちの建物にいます
I saw one in the medical room
医務室で見たよ
That's the one
それだ
Photo by Li Hong
写真提供：李紅
he holds the award
彼は賞を持っている
that good name that didn't last long
その良い名前は長くは続かなかった
He felt that he had seriously misspoken it.
彼は自分が重大な言い間違いをしたと感じた。
His name is Li Hongpi
彼の名前はリー・ホンピです
He also wants to promise you
彼もあなたに約束したいと思っています
please stand
お立ちください
It was sold to the general district of Minse City
ミンセ市一般地区に売却
He is also a material master
彼はマテリアルマスターでもあります
He helped us do half of the related
彼は私たちが関連する作業の半分を行うのを手伝ってくれました
This is my assistant Zhou Beita
こちらはアシスタントの周北太です
sent in the one who risked his life to do it
それをするために自分の命を危険にさらした人を送り込んだ
that situation
その状況
of our group
私たちのグループの
The sense of branching in that situation goes
その状況での分岐の感覚は行きます
is a lot of things
たくさんのことがある
That's Dr. Han
それはハン博士です
National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学
Prescription Medicine for Critical Illness
重篤な病気に対する処方薬
Follow the gymnastics from the Corleys
コーリー家の体操を見習いましょう
That's because everyone knows that
それは誰もが知っていることだから
Music in Taiwan is in very bad shape right now
台湾の音楽は今非常に悪い状況にある
So there are four major interfaces
したがって、4 つの主要なインターフェイスがあります
important reset
重要的重定的
All doctors are unwilling to come
医者はみんな来たがらない
A non-surgical
非外科的
So he's got it now
それで彼はもうそれを理解しました
He wants to be that Zifan himself
彼はあのジファン自身になりたいと思っている
Zifan's Zizi
ジファンのジジ
Then you have two kids
じゃあ子供が二人いるんだね
Then you have to talk to Mr.
それから、氏と話さなければなりません。
Zifan's Zifan wants to be with him
ジファンのジファンは彼と一緒にいたい
there are these
これらがあります
I want to read that again
もう一度読みたいです
very very right to him
彼にとってとてもとても正しい
This is it
これだよ
when this powerless
この無力なとき
he wears a high heel low
彼はハイヒールを低く履いています
just pronounce it
ただ発音してください
gotta find that
それを見つけなければなりません
very big
とても大きい
great indicator
素晴らしい指標
A very important payment is
非常に重要な支払いは、
I just found out that it is Red Soup Technology
レッドスープテクノロジーだと今知りました
if
もしも
If someone is buying refills
誰かが詰め替えを購入している場合
Mr.'s complement
氏の補足
Just make another one if you can make up for it
補えるならもう一つ作ればいい
make some adjustments
いくつかの調整をする
Gongzi Park
公子園
In the end, I would like to thank everyone for your advice.
最後に、アドバイスをくださった皆様に感謝したいと思います。
Of course he would like to thank the National Guest Association
もちろん、彼は全米ゲスト協会に感謝したいと思っています。
There are many universities in Zhuangdui
荘堆には大学がたくさんあります
There are many universities
大学はたくさんあります
then this is
それならこれは
I want to invite everyone
みんなを招待したいです
You have seen our host come
私たちのホストが来るのを見ましたね
so let me mention
それで言及させてください
Thank you everyone
感謝大家
platform one by one
プラットフォームを一つずつ
Because our article was published
弊社の記事が掲載されたため
When the article about drama was published
ドラマの記事が掲載されたとき
This enters everyone
これは誰でも入ります
then i will stop here
それならここでやめます
almost time
時間差不多
exactly twenty minutes
ちょうど20分
answer the questions
回答問題
in this way
この上
ok thank you all
わかりました、皆さんありがとう
that just had
それはちょうど持っていた
after already having an audience
すでに聴衆がいる後
That continuous sound is not good
あの連続音はダメだよ
then we start
それから始めましょう
that Q&A
そのQ&A
good
良い
Committee members
委員会メンバー
Um
えーっと
Thank you teacher for your wonderful speech
先生、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました
i think that place is
そこの場所だと思う
I mentioned that there are many kinds of antibiotics
抗生物質にはたくさんの種類があると言いました
In the experiment, we just talked about Wangu B&B
実験では、Wangu B&B について話しました。
Your information just now said
今言ったあなたの情報は
it's the outer skin of that cell
それはその細胞の外皮です
However, there is another data
ただし、別のデータもあります
Seems like a new one for protein synthesis
タンパク質合成の新しいもののようです
But protein synthesis is in that
しかし、タンパク質合成はその中にあります
Occurs in the center of large cells
大きな細胞の中心に発生します
like you just said
あなたが今言ったように
If the area of ​​the slide
スライドの領域の場合
that would be a big one
それは大きなことだろう
those things
それらのもの
when contained in the middle of the cell
細胞の中央に含まれる場合
your technique doesn't mean
あなたのテクニックは意味がありません
Should be close to that win
その勝利に近づくはずだ
It will be strengthened around that
その近くで強化されるだろう
then you are so far inside the cell
そうすればあなたは細胞のはるか内側にいる
can't you hear it
聞こえませんか
In fact the most likely
実は一番可能性が高いのは
I'm guessing of course
もちろん推測します
because i didn't see
見ていなかったので
that most likely is
それはおそらく
In fact, it's been a long time
実は、お久しぶりです
that cell
その細胞
bacteria are alive
細菌は生きている
so when its insides start to get attacked
それで内部が攻撃され始めると
and it starts emitting all kinds of different molecules
そしてあらゆる種類の異なる分子を放出し始めます
Then our goodness is actually
それでは、私たちの良さは実際には
The molecules emitted by the so-called scream
いわゆる叫びによって放出される分子
will eventually run until there is some running
最終的には実行中のものが存在するまで実行されます
what sounds do we hear when we come outside
外に出るとどんな音が聞こえますか
Then please don't ask me which molecule those sounds represent
それなら、その音がどの分子を表しているのかは聞かないでください
I've been doing this for so many years, I only dare to tell people
私はこれを何年も続けているので、あえて人にだけ言います。
I wish I could say it again here
ここでもう一度言えたらいいのですが
I hope
私は願います
this
これ
This 732 this Optics Valley
この 732 このオプティクス バレー
from which molecule
それはどの分子からのものですか?
because of all
すべてのせいで
Both Galanz and Young's bacteria have a very strong optical valley
ガランツ菌とヤング菌はどちらも非常に強い光学谷を持っています。
That's not what we saw in the lab
それは私たちが研究室で見たものではありません
This thing has been seen for 10 years
このことは10年前から見られています
I have been telling you for 3 years
3年間言い続けてきた
You said I wish my lab was the first to know
私の研究室が最初に知ってくれればよかったのにとあなたは言いました
Which molecule is that sound coming from?
その音はどの分子から出ているのでしょうか？
That
それか
I hope I'm still saying the same thing to you in less than 3 years
3年以内にまだ同じこと言ってるといいな
Doing basic research is a very hard work
基礎研究はとても大変な仕事です
but that thing
でもそれは
when you see a regularity
規則性が見えたとき
Why did Grand City and Yang Shijun have this signal
なぜグランドシティとヤン・シジュンはこの信号を持っていたのでしょうか？
The thing is that he has a regularity
問題は彼には規則性があるということだ
Like saying why the sun at what time of the year
なぜ一年のどの時期に太陽が出るのかと言っているようなもの
the longest days
日が一番長くなるだろう
When this thing is observed
こういうのを観察すると
Then when you go to understand the truth
そして真実を理解するとき
You may discover the three laws of overcoming
克服するための3つの法則が見つかるかもしれません
That's what attracts us
それが私たちを惹きつけるものです
That is, we are in a very complicated and complicated environment
つまり、私たちは非常に複雑で複雑な環境にいます
We suddenly hear a constant
突然定数が聞こえます
the constant
定数
There must be a reason behind it
その背後には必ず理由があるはずです
We have pursued for so many years
私たちは長年追求してきました
that's what you're asking
それがあなたが尋ねていることです
As for saying
言うことに関しては
people want to ask me to talk
人々は私に話したいと思っています
Is this word going to be useful? It's useless
この言葉は役に立つの? 役に立たない
Those things because of nano-country new Spanish
ナノカントリーの新しいスペイン語のせいでそれらのこと
Ask me every day if there is any industrial application
産業応用はないか毎日聞いてください
i have to say
私は言わないといけない
How much is the output value
出力値はいくらですか
let's talk to him
彼と話しましょう
if so
もしそうなら
I'll sell you a drama for 1 yuan
ドラマを1元で売ってあげる
Then we all sent
それからみんなで送りました
Everyone has a few hundred
誰もが数百個持っています
a gigabit like this
このようなギガビット
so this
したがって、この
this is an interesting question
これは興味深い質問です
I think it's the molecules
分子だと思います
What is the molecule that produces and teaches students?
生徒を生み出し、教える分子は何でしょうか?
i really have no way to answer
本当に答える方法がありません
And that's probably not the best thing to do
そして、それはおそらく最善のことではありません
because it changes too much
変わりすぎだから
when things are too complicated
物事が複雑すぎるとき
you have no way to answer
あなたには答える方法がありません
be a researcher
研究員になる
Maybe you have to measure whether you are old or not
自分が年をとっているかどうかを測る必要があるかもしれない
I'm about to retire
もうすぐ引退です
Then tell me how old you are
じゃあ何歳か教えて
can answer a certain type of question
特定のタイプの質問に答えることができる
All right
わかった
good
良い
second question
2番目の質問
do you sell that a crazy
あなたはそれをクレイジーに売りますか？
click it once
一度クリックしてください
Thanks
ありがとう
I remember one is
私が覚えているのは、その1つです
one of our present human rights
私たちの現在の人権の一つ
There is no avoidance of an advancement
進歩を避けることはできない
or like before playing a game
またはゲームをプレイする前のように
I think the life of things
物の命だと思います
we are doing such a job
私たちはそのような仕事をしています
The white snowball is bigger than the red wine
白い雪玉は赤ワインより大きい
Viruses are much smaller than bacteria
ウイルスは細菌よりもはるかに小さい
In fact such a spectrum
実際にはそのようなスペクトル
From Viruses From Viruses Such Spectrum
ウイルスから ウイルスから このようなスペクトル
is already done
すでに終わっています
I didn't do it because I didn't want to
やりたくないからやらなかった
but because of dealing with viruses
しかし、ウイルスを扱うため
I talked to him at the original branch
元の支店で彼と話しました
when i was studying bacteria
私が細菌を研究していたとき
All of our directors know how to make brows
当社のディレクターは全員、眉毛の作り方を知っています。
The lab guy next door said you were crazy
隣の研究室の人はあなたは頭がおかしいと言った
It's you who are going to poison us to death
私たちを毒殺するのはあなたです
you are going to kill us
あなたは私たちを殺すつもりですか
So the purpose of my coming today is
それで、今日私が来た目的は、
speak forcefully
強く話す
Professor Xu Mingda's point of view
徐明達教授の視点
is to give bacteria you supply
あなたが供給した細菌を与えることです
you have a kilo
あなたはキロ持っています
I have a kilo
私はキロ持っています
then you tell me
それからあなたは私に言います
I'm all comrades tell me
みんな同志だよ、教えてよ
you are going to kill me
あなたは私を殺すつもりですか
Who Killed Who?
誰が誰を殺したか?
I do not even know
私も知らない
I'm for this matter
私はこの件に関しては賛成です
I had to write another one
もう一つ書かなければならなかった
The Industrial Plan of Science and Technology Development Fund
科学技術発展基金産業計画
Then let's study what are xenobiotics
それでは、生体異物とは何かを勉強しましょう
someone was asking me before
前に誰かが私に尋ねていました
I am studying xenobiotics
私は生体異物を研究しています
Our laboratory only studies xenobiotics
私たちの研究室は生体異物のみを研究しています
You're wasting your yogurt every day
毎日ヨーグルトを無駄にしている
Then recently I found a very interesting topic
それから最近、非常に興味深いトピックを見つけました
I just wrote a letter today to a professor at the Central University
今日、私は中央大学の教授に手紙を書きました。
He is a xenobiotic of lactic acid-susceptible bacteria cultured from breast milk
彼は母乳から培養された乳酸感受性細菌の生体異物です
this is a very interesting idea
これはとても興味深いアイデアです
Because many children develop allergies
アレルギーを発症する子も多いので
The problem with every system is that they don't drink breast milk
すべてのシステムの問題は母乳を飲まないことです
If we feed him xenobiotics from breast milk
母乳から生体異物を与えたら
Then this thing may be a very, very likely effective motivator
そうすれば、これは非常に効果的な動機となる可能性があります
that's interesting
それは面白い
is the real effect of xenobiotics
これが生体異物の本当の効果です
The FDA all over the world has not said that he has an effect
世界中のFDAは彼に効果があるとは言っていない
That's what the manufacturers say
メーカーがそう言ってるよ
'Cause what they say they say the whole show
だって彼らが言うことはショー全体を通して言ってるから
No one can say he is right or wrong
彼が正しいとも間違っているとも誰も言えない
After that, there is another kind of xenobiotic bacteria that say yes
その後、別の種類の生体異物細菌があると言われています。
After drinking it, you can adjust your figure
飲むと体型調整ができる
I would also like to study this
これも勉強してみたいと思います
I'm currently working towards that direction
現在その方向に向けて取り組んでいます
For fear of being kicked out of National Taiwan University by my colleagues
同僚に台湾大学を追い出されるのを恐れて
So I'm going to start today by announcing
ということで今日はまず発表から始めます
please go out and talk
外に出て話してください
Professor Wang is studying probiotics
王教授はプロバイオティクスを研究している
May I ask if the Virus has any sound?
ウイルスに音があるかどうか聞いてもいいですか?
yes yes of course
はい、もちろん
As long as it is a molecule, it will have a sound
分子である限り音は出る
The voice actually says
その声は実際にこう言っている
atoms themselves do not oscillate
原子自体は振動しない
Then you take two green, green atoms
次に、緑色の原子を 2 つ取ります。
become a blue molecule
青い分子になる
it's right there when it rises
上がるとすぐそこにある
you can measure its frequency
その周波数を測定できます
that can now
それが今できる
Can this be applied to
これは適用できますか
the flu one
インフルエンザのやつ
theoretically possible
理論的には可能
But sample inferiority and collaborators are very important
ただし、サンプルの劣性と協力者は非常に重要です
Then if there is a Virus
それでウイルスがあったら
It's the influenza researcher.
インフルエンザ研究者です。
their laboratory
彼らの研究室
Whether it is a P3 or P4 laboratory
P3ラボかP4ラボか
Let's go and help him set up something like this
彼がこのようなものをセットアップするのを手伝いましょう
As long as he chats with me so that we all have a good time
私たち全員が楽しい時間を過ごせるように、彼が私とチャットしてくれる限り
I'm willing to send a set of machines over there to study with him
彼と一緒に勉強するために機械一式を向こうに送りたい
in this way
この上
i am very patient
私はとても忍耐強いです
For example, when we went to the Jilin Pavilion, we have sent that machine in for three or four years.
例えば、私たちが吉林館に行ったとき、その機械を3、4年送りました。
We have not published any articles
記事は一切公開していません
did not publish any articles
何も記事を公開しませんでした
we just keep doing it
私たちはただそれをやり続けるだけです
This is a philosophy that I personally do research on
これは私が個人的に研究している哲学です
Then I am not worried that Dean Synchronization sent me away
それならディーン同期に追い出されても心配ない
right
右
no two small problems
小さな問題は二つもない
One is Xijing's stage
一つは西京の舞台
that situation
その状況
Reaction of the young and old
老若男女の反応
There is another problem
別の問題があります
What's the reaction of Xijing's mix together?
西京のミックスの反応はどうですか？
These two things are what I really want to do
この２つが本当にやりたいことです
but i can only tell you now
でも今しか言えない
that's all mine
それはすべて私のものです
Just told my students the other day it was all mine
先日生徒たちに、それはすべて私のものだと言いました。
dream thing
夢のこと
but it's very interesting
でもとても面白いです
of course i will
もちろん
I put a careful one over there
あそこに慎重なものを置きました
then he watched him grow up
それから彼は彼の成長を見守った
that side grew up
そっち側は成長した
when he split
彼が別れたとき
He must have different molecules coming out
彼は別の分子が出てくるに違いない
At the moment when we are about to divide
別れようとするその瞬間に
does he exude
彼はにじみ出ていますか
when the child was born
子供が生まれたとき
This and that miserable student
あの悲惨な生徒たち
maybe everyone knows
たぶんみんな知ってる
Many female compatriots know
多くの女性同胞は知っています
That was when Mr. was beaten
氏が殴られたのはその時だった
is also miserable
も悲惨です
That miserable student
あの悲惨な生徒
can we hear
聞こえますか
This is all my Dream Experiment
これはすべて私の夢の実験です
But I've been speaking for five years
でも私は5年間話し続けてきた
My students get married and ignore me
生徒たちが結婚して私を無視する
so
それで
every time i tell them
私が彼らに言うたびに
This pair of XI-DEM
この XI-DEM のペア
then they all said
それから彼らは皆言いました
yes teacher
はい、先生
You are all XI-DEM
皆さんは XI-DEM です
so
それで
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう
turn off
消す
Hello Mr. Wang
こんにちは、王さん
I am in the doctor's office of Beijing Medical University
私は北京医科大学の医務室にいます
Now pronounce it Cantor
カントールと発音してください
Cantor's social development
カントールの社会発展
Do Cantor
ド・カントール
Metastases
転移
to transfer that research
その研究を移転するために
Just started
剛開始
Then what I want to ask is a
そこで聞きたいのは、
Expert in Pharmaceutical Physics and Chemistry
製薬物理学および化学の専門家
The problem with the second temperature is
2 番目の温度の問題は、
You recently saw the article
最近この記事を見ました
in cancer cells
がん細胞の中で
this cell it is doing
このセルはやっています
when it floats in the water
水に浮かんだとき
Then use laser two spectrum to pull it
次に、レーザー 2 スペクトルを使用してそれを引き出します
How do you know this Optic Tracer
この光学トレーサーをどのようにして知りましたか
Nayu that characteristic
なゆのあの特徴
How Q is it?
Qどうですか？
that elasticity
その弾力性
can represent how vicious it is
それがいかに悪質かを表すことができる
Then from normal cells
次に正常細胞から
one gets worse
片方が悪くなる
this becomes diversion
これは気晴らしになります
cancer cell
癌細胞
Finally it will transfer to that cell
最後にそのセルに転送されます
Its elasticity is getting more and more Q
弾力がどんどん増していきます Q
So the question I want to ask is
それで私が聞きたい質問は
Lamination
ラミネート加工
Cells can be studied in the middle of floating objects
浮遊物体の真ん中で細胞を研究できる
me because of my stuff
私のことのせいで私は
to magnify the matter
問題を拡大する
it can only be pasted
貼り付けることしかできません
So this is the limitation of this technique
これがこのテクニックの限界です
then you don't need to do this
それならこれをする必要はありません
You can consider doing Laman
レーマンを検討してみてはいかがでしょうか
That's because the cells are really big
それは細胞がとても大きいからです
so you know it floats over there
だからそこに浮かんでいることがわかります
Then you use an Optic Tracer
次に、光学トレーサーを使用します
after grabbing it
それを掴んだ後
You use laser light on it
レーザー光を使用します
same laser light
同じレーザー光
you measure its luster
あなたはその輝きを測ります
You hope to directly get the slow and wide service under the different pulling force of the cell itself
セル自体の異なる引っ張り力の下で、低速で幅広いサービスを直接取得したいと考えています
you can get it
がんばって
I don't know how to explain it after pulling it
引いた後はどう説明したらいいのか分からない
But this is a very interesting experiment
しかし、これは非常に興味深い実験です
But I also tell my students that it is also my dream experiment.
しかし、私は生徒たちにも、これは私の夢の実験でもあるとも伝えています。
But if you want to do that, you are welcome to come to our lab to do it
でも、それをやりたいなら、ぜひ私たちの研究室に来てください。
good
良い
That Wang novel is because a lot of people just talked about the virus
ワンの小説は、多くの人がウイルスについて話したばかりだからです
Well, we have that insect virus.
さて、私たちはその昆虫ウイルスを持っています。
Then this is usable and has been approved for safety.
そうすれば、これは使用可能であり、安全性が認められています。
So a virus that is absolutely harmless to humans
人間には全く無害なウイルスなので、
and it can be saved
そしてそれは保存できる
Then this is
それからこれは
You'll go viral in no time
すぐに広まりますよ
real
本物
What about the flu virus just now?
今のインフルエンザウイルスはどうですか？
The flu virus is indeed that they are very unkempt
インフルエンザウイルスは確かに非常にボサボサです
I don't know what happens to people's stomachs
人のお腹はどうなるか分からない
Then I don't have a virus now, but I am infected with a virus, and I look neat
じゃあ、今はウイルスに感染してないけど、ウイルスに感染してるのに、見た目はきれいなんだよ
So I guess it might be better to read the light map
なのでライトマップを読んだ方が良いかもしれません
Then it involves the pick you just mentioned
それから、先ほど言ったピックも関係します
What molecule does it represent?
それはどのような分子を表しているのでしょうか?
Maybe it's infected with a virus
もしかしたらウイルスに感染しているかも知れません
I said that insects can help with a similar answer
昆虫も同様の答えをくれると言いました
That means we can take that
つまり、それを受け取ることができます
Influenza's surface protein called Hemagotinin
ヘマゴチニンと呼ばれるインフルエンザの表面タンパク質
It is the obvious element that is the most important antigen
最も重要な抗原であることは明白な要素です
can be transplanted onto virus-infected surfaces
ウイルスに感染した表面に移植できる
So in this case
したがって、この場合には
You can read that molecule's pick
その分子の選択を読み取ることができます
I'm guessing because I'm leading the way and don't understand at all
私がリードしていて理解できないから推測します
but i mean, the flu
でもつまり、インフルエンザ
a lot of protein on it
たんぱく質がたくさん入っている
You can't quite figure out exactly what protein you're reading about
どのタンパク質について読んでいるのか正確に理解できない
But if you move its protein to the time when the virus is infected for 3 minutes
しかし、そのタンパク質をウイルスが感染した時間に3分間移動すると、
You will see, because the infection virus must have its original spectrum
ご覧のとおり、感染ウイルスは独自のスペクトルを持っているはずです。
Then you have one more protein, the protein is quite big
それからもう 1 つのタンパク質があります。このタンパク質はかなり大きいです
you will see a special pick
特別なピックが表示されます
I'll start off by saying that we maybe the two of us should sit down
まず、二人で座ったほうがいいかもしれないと言うことから始めます
like the failure to say that two people chatted
二人でおしゃべりしたことを言い忘れたように
yes , yes , are dating your colleagues
はい、はい、はい、あなたの同僚と付き合っています
Today's A election is not suitable for talking about such reality
今日のA選挙はそんな現実を語るのにはふさわしくない
short story just one sentence
たった一文だけの短い物語
that is, not every molecule of every
つまり、すべての分子がすべてではないのです。
I just showed you the vibration
振動をお見せしただけです
you can hear every sound
あらゆる音を聞くことができます
because it has the problem of choosing symmetry
対称性を選択するという問題があるからです
So there are some vibrating mannequins
振動するマネキンがいくつかあります
it is impossible to vibrate out
振動で出すことは不可能です
so you're pretty sure
だからあなたはかなり確信しています
I put this protein on
このプロテインを塗ってみました
doesn't mean you can hear it
聞こえるというわけではありません
this is called
これは呼ばれます
in quantum mechanics
量子力学で
selection problem
selection的問題
So this is what we're going to talk about in more detail
それでは、これについて詳しく説明していきます
When it comes to this level
このレベルになると
I think we are more suitable to do in
でやるのが私たちの方が適していると思います
the two of us wait a minute and we'll go get coffee
二人でちょっと待って、コーヒーを飲みに行きます
Then make a model
それから模型を作ります
mold
型
OK
OK
It's more appropriate for us to talk in private.
私たちにはプライベートで話すほうが適切です。
good
良い
Teacher, your speech is really touching
先生、あなたのスピーチは本当に感動的です
Then the question I want to extend is to say
そこで私が拡張したい質問はこう言います
Because the current platform is
なぜなら、現在のプラットフォームは
is on the fix the plate
プレートを修正中です
Is it possible for us
私たちにも可能でしょうか？
convert it to a format
フォーマットに変換する
For example, it looks like a pig
たとえば、豚に似ています
Is it possible for him to become like a missile?
彼がミサイルのようになる可能性はありますか？
Go to our Target with something like this
次のようなものでターゲットに移動します
For example, cancers that are hard to find and detect
たとえば、発見や発見が難しいがんなどです。
Hard-to-find things like lung cancer or soft-slot cancer
肺がんやソフトスロットがんなどの発見が難しいもの
Someone is doing such a laboratory
こんな研究室をやっている人がいる
but that means
しかしそれは意味します
is that theoretically you make some molecules on top of the surface
理論的には、表面の上にいくつかの分子を作るということです
Those molecules are theoretically conceivable
それらの分子は理論的に考えられる
Then he likes cancer and doesn't like cancer
それから彼は癌が好きで癌は好きではありません
These are our own wishes
これらは私たち自身の願いです
Then go down and find
それから下に行って見つけてください
At this time, let's go back to the issue of the white grass hidden in the Shenlong room that I just talked about.
ここで、先ほどの神龍の部屋に隠された白い草の問題に戻りましょう。
Then maybe you should talk to Dean Wang Qihui about this issue
それなら、この問題についてディーン・ワン・チーフイと話し合ったほうがいいかもしれません
Then if the molecule you found has been found
そして、見つけた分子が見つかったら
Then I said I'm wrapping it on a magnetic bead now
それから私は今それを磁気ビーズで包んでいると言いました
Then I use magnetic beads to pull it out with a magnetic field
次に磁気ビーズを使って磁場で引き抜きます
This kind of thing has been done for ten or twenty years.
このようなことは10年、20年前から行われています。
Then this has nothing to do with the spectrum we just talked about today.
それでは、これは私たちが今日話したスペクトルとは何の関係もありません。
Is there anyone doing that kind of experiment?
そういう実験をしている人はいますか？
doing now
今やっている
In fact, someone is looking for
実は探している人がいる
Secure the In-Tool Mo'Share
ツール内の Mo'Share を保護する
For example, our base center
たとえば、当社の拠点センター
Professor Zhang Yingzhi in the Foundation Center
財団センターの張英志教授
you can go talk to everyone
みんなと話しに行ってもいいよ
He has a special problem in doing this
彼はこれを行う際に特別な問題を抱えている
If so
もしそうなら
Do you want to do experiments like that
そんな実験してみませんか
i don't understand at all
全く分かりません
You go to talk to Zhang Yingzhi and the others
張英志たちと話をしに行く
There may be a better way to answer more accurately
より正確に答えるためのより良い方法があるかもしれません
That's because I'm using the way I'm familiar with
それは私が使い慣れた方法を使っているからです
that their way
それは彼らのやり方です
I'm more obsessive
私はもっ​​と執着的です
So you should still talk to an expert
したがって、やはり専門家に相談する必要があります
OK
OK
Thanks
ありがとう
good
良い
he first and then you
最初に彼、それからあなた
Professor Wang please
王先生お願いします
The area just mentioned refers to the two atomic groups
先ほど述べた領域は 2 つの原子団を指します。
be close enough
十分近くにいる
Or must two nanometer atoms be close enough
または、2 ナノメートルの原子が十分に接近している必要があります
no no
いやいや
Nano particles are not atoms
ナノ粒子は原子ではありません
inside a nanoparticle
ナノ粒子の内部
Like the one at 25, there is still
25歳の時と同じように、まだある
There are 1 million atoms in a particle of 25 nanometers
25ナノメートルの粒子には100万個の原子が含まれています
25 nanometers and 1 million atoms
25ナノメートルと100万個の原子
So atoms are much smaller than that
つまり、原子はそれよりもはるかに小さいのです
Atoms are very, very small
原子はとてもとても小さいです
i can tell you
教えられます
Our surface nails are so big
私たちの表面の爪はとても大きいです
I dial a layer of atoms down
原子の層をダイヤルダウンします
just dial it down
ただダイヤルダウンしてください
every atom
すべての原子
If anyone wants to buy one from me
誰か私から買いたい人がいたら
a dollar
ドル
that total cost
その総費用
Yes, our national budget can last for a thousand years
そう、私たちの国家予算は千年も続くのです
But I sell you atoms for a year
しかし、私はあなたに原子を1年間売ります
Our Institute of Atomic and Molecular Research has started selling atoms
私たち原子分子研究所が原子の販売を開始しました
Just peel off the top of my nails
爪の上から剥がすだけ
Just drop so much every day
毎日たくさん落とすだけ
so what are you asking
それで何を聞いているのですか
what about this hot zone
このホットゾーンはどうですか
The hot zone is these two
ホットゾーンはこの2つ
Two lumps of a million atoms
100万個の原子の2つの塊
This is durable
これは耐久性があります
very very close
とてもとても近い
by the distance between them
彼らの間の距離によって
about twenty atoms
約20個の原子
when i only have that distance
その距離しかないとき
The laser light in the middle comes in and says
真ん中のレーザー光が入ってきてこう言う
form a strong consensus
強い合意を形成する
Inside those million atoms
その百万個の原子の中に
and more than a million electrons
そして100万個以上の電子
That electron flies to the electricity
その電子は電気に飛んでいきます
when you stand up
あなたが立ち上がるとき
they seem to be out of alignment
それらはずれているようです
like a
のような
one is twice
1つは2倍です
right next to your ear
あなたの耳のすぐ隣に
then
それから
That's very powerful, that is to say, the molecule in the middle emits a very intense light.
これは非常に強力です。つまり、真ん中の分子が非常に強い光を発します。
That's what this whole story is about
これがこの物語全体の内容です
It was an unexpected discovery that only two
たった2つしかなかったのは予想外の発見でした
Then our contribution is that when we turn stupid beans into ice at once, it is the rule of hundreds of millions of rows
そして、私たちの貢献は、愚かな豆を一度に氷に変えるとき、それが数億行の法則であるということです
make it fast
早くしてください
Then it is like a net to be on top of it
その上に網があるようなものです
That is a bacterium with a thousand of these nanometers underneath
それはその下に何千ナノメートルもの細菌がある
Therefore, the whole signal is relatively high from the revival and the stability is also good.
そのため、復活から全体の信号が比較的高く、安定性も良好です。
are relative
相対的なものである
So the nanometer refers to its distance not its length
したがって、ナノメートルは長さではなく距離を指します
Then you refer to each distance
次に、それぞれの距離を参照します
is the distance between the two of them is the interval
二人の間の距離は間隔です
Between strong disadvantages and strong disadvantages
強いデメリットと強いデメリットの間
Their average distance is thirty nanometers
それらの平均距離は30ナノメートルです
there is one in the middle
真ん中に1つあります
A gap with nanometers is a gap
ナノメートルの隙間は隙間
That gap is still the worst place for the confrontation
そのギャップは依然として対立にとって最悪の場所である
Sound is from vibrations between two atoms
音は2つの原子間の振動から発生します
that's how to strengthen it
それが強化する方法です
It's the function of the flat nanosphere
平面ナノスフィアの働きです
Wang Zhongsheng, do you have
王忠生さん、持っていますか？
Then you are very reluctant to say
そうすると、あなたは非常に言いたがりません。
Hope is by means of visual molecules
希望は視覚分子によって生まれる
on a metal surface
金属表面に
Then the specific light comes down
すると特定の光が降りてくる
reflected by it
それによって反映される
Specific inside light map
特定の内部ライトマップ
Then look at the general idea of ​​its molecules
次に、その分子の一般的な概念を見てみましょう
in that and that chemistry
あれやこれやの化学の中で
The Khing Lim Finger that mentions Bohr
ボーアについて言及した『キング・リムの指』
mention the first layer
最初の層について言及する
and then absorb specific ingredients
そして特定の成分を吸収します
Then Yaoqing went back to the basic one
それからYaoqingは基本的なものに戻りました
Tell me which grade you are in first
最初に何年生か教えてください
I am a sophomore in Yanfeng Middle School
私は延豊中学校の2年生です
Then you are very, very good
それならあなたはとてもとても上手です
you just said
あなたは今言いました
You're talking about ball picking chemistry
あなたはボール拾いの化学について話しています
OK good
いいよ
very good
とても良い
that one thing is different
その一つが違うということ
That is also the energy level of the main circle of electrons
それは電子の主円のエネルギー準位でもある
Now we're talking about a party between two atoms
今、私たちは 2 つの原子間のパーティーについて話しています。
Electronic circle is
電子サークルは
Electrons are much lighter than atoms
電子は原子よりもはるかに軽い
should know
知っておくべき
e.g. for example
たとえば、たとえば
is the weight of light atoms
軽い原子の重さです
It is the difference between the weight of a direct son and an electron
直息子と電子の重さの違いです
It's two thousand times worse
それは2000倍悪いです
People often don't understand
人々は理解できないことが多い
The difference between that electron and ours is that
その電子と私たちの電子の違いは、
if you are if you are electronic
あなたが電子的な場合
That light atom is the lesson of the M60
あの軽い原子はM60の教訓だ
so electrons are small
つまり電子は小さいのです
will wrap around
包み込むでしょう
Is there just one electron?
電子は1つだけですか？
Then this electron has various orbital domains
この電子にはさまざまな軌道ドメインがあります
when it starts beating
鼓動し始めると
it also glows
それも光ります
Then this is the other one called
それから、これはもう一つと呼ばれるものです
A spectrum emitted by electrons
電子が発するスペクトル
That's an electronic spectrum
それは電子スペクトルです
That's not what we're talking about now
今話しているのはそういうことではない
Talking about a handful of two
一握りの二人について話す
When the golden circles are placed together
金色の丸を並べると
One of their mother's relatives
彼らの母親の親戚の一人
The middle character of these two parent characters
これら 2 つの親文字の真ん中の文字
can be proved like this
このように証明できます
like dumbbells
ダンベルのように
can go over there
あそこに行けるよ
It turns out that it can be proved like this
このように証明できることが分かりました
Then this has a legitimate frequency
そうすると、これは正当な頻度になります
this legitimate frequency
この正当な頻度
That's what I just said
それが私が今言ったことです
The sound we just played to you
今君に奏でた音
multiply by 3 by 10 the house of the cross
3×10を掛ける 十字架の家
I just lied to you on purpose
私はわざとあなたに嘘をついただけです
Just take that 3 times 10 cross room
10クロスルームを3倍するだけです
just remove it
それを取り除くだけです
So deliberately pretend that there is no such number
だから意図的にそのような数字は存在しないふりをする
then you hear
それからあなたは聞きます
It's actually that simple
実はとても簡単なことなのです
OK, here's the one that plays
OK、再生するのはこれです
It's all a lie to you
それはすべてあなたにとって嘘です
Professor Na Huang
ナ・ファン教授
you just mentioned
あなたは今言いました
no way to know now
今となっては知る由もない
That frequency is specially bought a molecule
その周波数は特別に購入された分子です
is there a way to do this
これを行う方法はありますか
There is a way
やり方がある
It's theoretically possible
理論的には可能だよ
but that's called need
でもそれは必要と呼ばれるものです
very very hardworking graduate student
とてもとても勤勉な大学院生
Well, we don't have people like that
まあ、うちにはそんな人いないけどね
Thanks
ありがとう
ok one last question
はい、最後に質問です
Hello, Mr. Wang, I would like to ask
こんにちは、王さん、お聞きしたいのですが
Because of your research, I remember that there was a press conference last year or the year before
あなたの調査のおかげで、昨年か一昨年に記者会見があったことを覚えています
At that time, it was said that this method could quickly screen the pathogenic bacteria of septicemia
当時、この方法は敗血症の原因菌を迅速にスクリーニングできると言われていました。
Then I want to ask if so far
それでは、これまでのところどうかを聞きたいです
For example, it was reported by National Taiwan University Hospital
たとえば、国立台湾大学病院によって報告されました。
Has that big hospital used this method in clinical practice?
あの大きな病院は臨床現場でこの方法を使ったことがありますか？
i and they already hinted to you
私と彼らはすでにあなたに示唆しました
That is when you start to really face the reproductive world
それが生殖の世界に真剣に向き合い始めるときです
the pain just started
痛みは始まったばかりです
When you write a thesis, all your imagination is very pure
論文を書くとき、あなたの想像力はすべて非常に純粋です
But when you get a drop of blood
でも、一滴の血が出たら
My first thing is that it's still blood from a healthy person.
まず第一に、それはまだ健康な人からの血液であるということです。
The nurse lady mentioned it to me first
看護師の女性が最初に私にそれを言いました
Teacher, there are many patients' blood in the blood of real patients
先生、本物の患者の血にはたくさんの患者の血が入っています
Half a barrel is filled with oil floating on top
バレルの半分が満たされており、その上に石油が浮いている
Because he eats very well
彼はよく食べるので
So eat half of it, maybe the oil will be lower
だから半分食べて、油が減るかもしれない
just listen to all the voices
ただすべての声を聞いてください
to the sound of oil
油の音に合わせて
then we have to go on
それなら続けなければなりません
So it's all the same
だから全部同じだよ
like there is actually another
まるで実際には別のものがあるかのように
A very frequently asked question is to say
よく聞かれる質問は次のとおりです
Then, for example, in mainland China
そして、例えば中国本土では
Everyone three together in peace
みんなで3人仲良く
Is there Sanjuqing'an in the milk?
牛乳に三酒清庵は入っていますか？
Of course, this method can also
もちろん、この方法でも可能です
It must be all right
きっと大丈夫だよ
There are also people doing such research
そういう研究をしている人もいる
The first thing you need to do is put the milk
まずは牛乳を入れます
Other impurities in the milk powder must be disposed of first
粉ミルクに含まれるその他の不純物は、最初に廃棄する必要があります。
That's all very deep chemistry
それはすべて非常に奥深い化学です
Maybe our vice president can answer
たぶん私たちの副社長が答えてくれるでしょう
I'm just starting to regret it
ただ後悔し始めている
When my blog researcher was interviewed by a reporter
私のブログ研究者が記者からインタビューを受けたとき
some of the questions he answered
彼が答えた質問のいくつか
Because people have a very strange
なぜなら人々は非常に奇妙なものを持っているからです
That's when the reporters start asking you
そのとき記者たちがあなたに質問し始めます
The more he talks, the happier he is.
彼は話せば話すほど幸せになります。
Then Wen Tang said
するとウェン・タンはこう言った。
You decide how long it will take to finish
完了するまでにどれくらいの時間がかかるかを決めるのはあなたです
I said it should be over in 30 minutes
30分で終わるって言ったのに
Because we have a close relationship
コールド・ディールがあるから
It'll cool down in about 5 minutes.
5分ほどで冷めます。
But I don't think so
でも私はそうは思わない
that sample pretreatment
サンプルの前処理
It might take half a day to deal with that or something.
それを処理するのに半日かかるかもしれません。
you really want something that works for the patient
患者にとって有効なものが本当に欲しいと思っている
It takes a lot of practice
たくさんの練習が必要です
So my answer to your question should be clear enough
したがって、あなたの質問に対する私の答えは十分に明確であるはずです
That is to say, we went in very hard.
つまり、かなり頑張って入りました。
Never move the machine in
決して機械を室内に移動させないでください
Then I have been doing experiments for others
それから私は他の人のために実験を行ってきました
Every day is very depressing
毎日がとても憂鬱です
Been doing something I don't understand at all
全く理解できないことをしている
just how to put
ちょうどどのように置くか
front of blood
血の正面
something that has nothing to do with this matter
この件とは関係のないこと
Then I can use a
それから私は使うことができます
Talk about the first sentence of Ke Wenzhe's meeting with me in one minute
柯文哲氏と私との面会の最初の一文について1分で話してください
I asked him
彼に聞いた
Dr. Ke
ケ博士
this
これ
Halfblood is really sick, you can see he's dying
ハーフブラッドは本当に病気だ、彼が死につつあるのは目に見えている
Then there are probably a few bacteria in the blood he sucked.
となると、彼が吸った血液にはおそらく数個の細菌が含まれていると思われます。
because i'm going to catch
捕まえるから
then you always give me one
それならあなたはいつも私に一つくれます
Just say that I want to go to a mountain as big as a mountain
山と同じくらい大きな山に行きたいとだけ言ってください
to catch the mountain machine
マウンテンマシンを捕まえるために
Then you always tell me how many machines there are in that mountain
それからあなたはいつもその山に何台の機械があるかを教えてくれます
I wouldn't miss it
見逃せないよ
Ke Wenzhe is very like that
柯文哲はまさにそれです
like he was repeatedly told on tv
テレビで何度も言われていたように
Professor Huang
黄教授
we should be in this world
私たちはこの世界にいるべきです
no one can answer
誰も答えられない
This big question should be taken to the people
この大きな問いは人々に問いかけられるべきである
Then of course I don't believe it
それならもちろん信じないよ
Then I really want to say yes when we
それなら、私は本当に「はい」と言いたいです。
so i just say
だから私はただ言います
I go abroad everywhere
私はどこへでも海外に行きます
Those outside China may want to cooperate with us
中国国外の人は私たちに協力したいと思うかもしれません
very big visit
非常大的要訪
everyone is about home
みんな家についている
what you're really doing
あなたは本当に何をしているのですか
he also told me
彼も私に言いました
1CC inside
1CC内側
probably at most 1 to 5
おそらく多くても 1 ～ 5
only tinnitus
耳鳴りだけ
doesn't seem genuine
本物ではないようです
In that 1CC of blood
その1CCの血液の中に
What does 1 to 5 mean
1から5は何を意味しますか
let me tell you again
もう一度言わせてください
1cc of blood
血液1cc
Then you replace it with
次に、それを次のように置き換えます
primary bacteria
一次細菌
That 1CC of blood
その血液1CC
How big is 1CC?
1CCってどれくらいの大きさですか？
Because our fund is 1 million times
うちのファンドは100万倍なので
That 1CC
その1CC
1CC is 3CC in 1 cm
1CCは1cmで3CCです
then you convert it
それからそれを変換します
How big is that soup
そのスープはどのくらいの大きさですか
I convert it
変換します
For Taipei City
台北市行き
You put it as high as Seven Star Mountain
七星山と同じくらい高く置いたね
fill it all with water
すべてを水で満たしてください
Taipei may be completely flooded with water
台北が完全に水浸しになる可能性
there is a
ある
Ke Wenzhe is swimming there
柯文哲はそこで泳いでいます
then you say
それからあなたは言います
that's some things to do
それはやるべきことがある
The difficulty is of course very difficult.
難易度は当然ながら非常に難しい。
So biologists don't do such stupid things
だから生物学者はそんな愚かなことはしない
Biologists say let's bring it
生物学者はそれを持ち込もうと言っています
Then every half hour it changes to two
その後、30分ごとに2つに変わります
Then do it for another half an hour and it turns into four
それからさらに 30 分続けると 4 時間になります
Then just wait for three days, right?
それなら3日くらい待ってくださいね？
and then on the second
そして二番目に
Twenty and forty parties are coming
20、40のパーティーが来ます
catch one
1つ捕まえる
Then they are all the same ethnic group
それならみんな同じ民族だよ
then you go and listen to him
それからあなたは行って彼の話を聞きます
Why are you grabbing one, right?
なぜそれを掴んでいるのですか？
Then it starts to become something
それから何かになり始める
very strange question like this
このような非常に奇妙な質問
If you catch it, you won't get it, and you won't talk about it.
理解できても理解できないし、それについて話さないでしょう。
but it's not true
しかしそれは真実ではありません
So I'm looking for him to catch that one
だから私は彼にそれを捕まえてもらうのを探しています
Not because I envy you too much
羨ましすぎるからじゃない
But because of that one thing
でも、その一つのせいで
to catch him
彼を捕まえるために
There are many physical and chemical grids that are very far away
非常に遠く離れた物理的および化学的グリッドが多数あります
Its a very high question in this challenge circle
このチャレンジサークルでは非常に高い質問です
your first reaction is to say
あなたの最初の反応はこう言うことです
Then I will take all the water in Taipei City
じゃあ台北市内の水を全部持っていきます
Is it all leaking?
全部漏れてるのかな？
Then I'm the one in the water
じゃあ水の中にいるのは私だ
Just dig a hole in the city hall
市役所に穴掘ってみろよ
The others with that bacterial blue column
他の人たちはバクテリアの青い柱を持っています
Everything can be done in Ximika
Ximika ですべてを行うことができます
All the other honeys are gone
他の蜂蜜はすべてなくなった
And then take it off when it's big
そして大きくなったら脱ぐ
it's easy to say
言うのは簡単です
real things to do
本当にやるべきこと
Most of the holes are plugged in
ほとんどの穴は塞がってます
then there too
それならそこにも
So then you can't pretend
それでは、ふりをすることはできません
but encouragement from there every day
でもそこから毎日励まされる
then just say
それならただ言ってください
Many questions are asked every day
毎日たくさんの質問が寄せられます
what's on your mind
何を考えているの
So the real world
だから現実世界
Actually something that works
実際に機能するもの
it costs a lot of money
たくさん費用がかかる
These things are far from basic research
これらは基礎研究とは程遠いものです
So once there is a breakthrough in basic research
したがって、基礎研究にブレークスルーがあれば、
It can definitely help a lot of things
それは間違いなく多くのことに役立ちます
So I'm going to talk about it here
だからここでそれについて話します
That is to say, Chinese College
つまり中国アカデミー
Chinese studies are in great need of everyone's support
中国研究は皆さんの支援を大いに必要としています
Chinese studies also need to be resolved
中国研究も解決する必要がある
good
良い
I'm usually very good at timing
普段はタイミングがとても上手です
because it was supposed to be 11 o'clock
11時の予定だったので
end at 9 o'clock
9時に終わる
He has two minutes of timeout on his
彼には2分間のタイムアウトがある
good
良い
Our congratulations thank you Huang Yan
おめでとうございます、黄岩さんに感謝します